[Cian] What do you think love is?
[sighs]
It can make people do crazy things
that they wouldn't think of doing,
make them act all bizarre.
I think it requires, um, communication,
honesty, and compromise.
[narrator] Maddi and Mark
are going on their second date
at the Australian Museum.
Mark is hoping to impress her
with his dinosaur knowledge.
- Hey, Maddi.
- Hi, Mark. How are you?
- Nice to see you again.
- Good to see you. Hey.
- How are you?
- Good, and you?
Awesome.
- [Maddi] Haven't been here in ages.
- [Mark] Well, you're gonna love it.
Here we are, lo and behold,
- the dinosaur exhibit.
- [Maddi] Ooh.
[Mark] You know who these guys are?
They're raptors.
- Raptors.
- You might remember them
from movies like Jurassic Park
or documentaries.
Oh, I couldn't watch those movies.
I tried to.
It's just too much violence and gore.
It's like, oh, my God.
[Mark] Check out that toe claw.
- [Maddi] Yeah, it's so long and sharp.
- [Mark] Yes.
You could take someone's eye out.
And it's very good
for killing its prey with.
- How about that, eh?
- Yes.
[Mark] This one's from Africa,
Nigersaurus.
That's a Hypsilophodon.
It's a cute little dinosaur.
Sure. [chuckles]
[Mark] When they discovered
the Sinornithosaurus,
it sent shock waves
throughout the paleontological community.
This is Maiasaura.
The name Maiasaura means "good mother."
- Well, there you go.
- Yeah.
This is the femur
of the sauropod dinosaurs.
Some of them are so big, you can't even
wrap your arms around them.
- Here's my old favorite, Stegosaurus.
- [Maddi] Stegosaurus.
Minmi.
- Minmi?
- Yeah.
It's an Ankylosaurus.
Here's a really cool dinosaur.
Cryolophosaurus.
Oh.
[Mark] Interesting fact.
Tyrannosaurus Rex has the strongest,
the most powerful bite
of any other dinosaur.
- [Maddi] Yeah.
- Truly a formidable predator.
[Cian] Is it going well so far?
Oh, yeah.
I've hardly been... I haven't been...
I haven't been able to get
much, um, sentences in,
because he's always
just, like, saying something.
But that's okay, like...
It's fine, so...
[birds chirping]
Ah, perfect.
[Mark exhales]
That was love.
Ah, this is perfect.
Yeah, fabulous.
[Mark] Such a beautiful place.
[Maddi] Yeah.
- Nice.
- [Mark exhales]
Just feel that breeze.
It's like Mother Nature is giving you
a nice welcoming kiss.
Hadn't thought about it like that.
[Mark sighs]
One day, um, Ma...
Um, Maddi, one day,
if you found the perfect guy,
would you like to get married?
Um...
Well...
Maybe, I think... I think
that's kind of a question...
when... when I find that someone...
- Yeah.
- ...and kinda if.
Do you feel anything about me?
Um... [chuckles]
- I know...
- Oh, jeez. Um...
- Yeah.
- Oh, look...
I think you're a very nice guy,
very smart, and very interesting.
Yeah.
And very good friend material.
- Yeah.
- I just...
There's no romantic feelings, like...
That happens a lot.
But, uh, I think you're beautiful.
You're smart as well.
- Oh, thank you.
- And you... you're very enthusiastic.
I think you have
excellent friend material.
There's nothing wrong with being friends.
- Yeah, yeah.
- You know...
- At least I made a new friend.
- Yes, yes.
That's the wonderful gift of life.
Yeah. [chuckles]
- Well...
- Okay.
- It's been a wonderful day.
- Yeah, it has been quite an experience.
- I wish you all the best.
- Thank you.
I hope you take care of yourself.
- I wish you all the best for the future.
- You too.
- All right.
- You as well.
- Okay.
- Well, goodbye.
Bye.
[Maddi] I've never had romantic feelings
for anyone.
And I'm not sure, like...
if it hasn't happened by now,
it might not happen, you know? So, like...
Like, maybe it will happen
if I meet the right person, but, like...
And because I never experienced it,
maybe I don't know
how to read the signs, or...
pick up the emotions, or whatever.
Hey, Mark.
- Hey, Dad.
- [father] How'd you go?
- Great, we had a wonderful time.
- Great? Well done. Good on ya, fella.
So, what happened?
Well, we... we're not really...
compatible.
Oh, okay. That's fine.
- We always said that might be the case.
- Yeah.
Well, to be honest,
I feel a little bit sad.
Yeah, I understand.
- And so, you left on a good note, though?
- Yeah.
- A happy note?
- We're both friends, so...
- Right.
- That's all we can...
That's all we can ask for.
- Yeah.
What do you think? Ready to go home?
- Yeah. It's been a long day.
- Yeah.
Okey-doke, let's go.
[squawks]
All right, shall we check this place out?
Oh, it's amazing.
[narrator] Things might not have
worked out with Maddi,
but Mark hasn't given up
in his search for love.
Today he's meeting his friend Ryan
for some dating advice.
[Mark] Good thing this table's free.
Yeah, this is the best one in the place.
[slight chuckle]
What's going on in your life
at the moment?
- You've been searching for dates?
- Yeah.
Maddi was a nice person.
But...
unfortunately, we didn't have
any romantic spark between us.
- Oh, man.
- We were more keen to friends.
- [waitress] Banana smoothie?
- That's me.
- [waitress] There you go.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Cheers for that.
That is interesting.
Ah, yes, nothing like a nice cup of tea
on a wonderful afternoon like this.
That's true.
And that banana smoothie
looks really nice,
I've got to admit.
[Mark] So, what do you think girls like?
Humor.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
And I do think, to get a girl to like you,
is to flatter them.
Oh, yes, definitely.
Because they have feelings
just like we do.
Would you prefer a girl who has
the same interest in dinosaurs?
That would be wonderful.
Yeah.
[Mark] It's a huge world.
Anything is possible.
I mean, I like dinosaurs too,
but not an obsession.
Well, I'm madly in love.
- I'm sure you are. [chuckles]
- Yeah. [chuckles]
Mmm.
Are you, uh, dating anyone?
Not officially.
- Okay, right.
- Yeah.
I'm still looking.
Well, stay strong. You know,
someone will come along and...
will be right for you.
Yes, my soul mate is out there,
I just haven't found her yet.
Yeah. It will happen.
- It will happen.
- Yep.
- Are you on any dating sites,
like Plenty of Fish or eharmony?
Oh, yes, I've looked into dating sites.
Even int...
Yeah?
Even international dating sites.
- [chuckles]
- International dating sites, interesting.
I could picture myself with a, uh,
Mexican girl on my right shoulder
and a Russian girl on my left shoulder.
[Mark laughs]
[Ryan] Yeah...
I guess I'm the international lover
kind of guy.
Ah, okay.
- Yeah.
- All right.
Well, that was great...
- Oh, sure.
- ...having time with you.
Thanks.
I had a wonderful time,
and I hope we do this again.
- Oh, sure, my pleasure.
- You take care, Ryan.
- Pleasure, as always.
- Wish you all the best.
- [Ryan] Thanks, you too.
- Have a good day.
- Good luck with your search.
- [Mark] I will. You too.
- Thanks. [chuckles]
- See ya, Ryan.
- [Ryan chuckles] See ya, Mark.
- Take care.
[Cian] How do you feel about
being on the autism spectrum?
I have mixed emotions, you know.
Even though I'm on the spectrum,
I'm still capable of falling in love
and being a compassionate
and caring person.
[Cian] And have you ever had
a relationship?
- No.
- [Cian] So, falling in love
- is something you would like to do?
- Oh.
For a long time, yes.
It's always been on my mind,
and it's just so hard to get.
This is a skull of a Tyrannosaurus Rex,
I'm very proud of it, you know.
I basically worship it.
This is by a paleo artist.
This guy here is a grade A,
bona fide dinosaur.
It has a small sail on its back.
In the mating season,
you would want to show that off
and say, "Hey, baby, look at me.
I'm the one you want to mate with."
[Cian] Can you describe for me
your ideal partner?
I like a girl who is very passionate,
at the same time, a very...
calm and caring nature.
[Cian] What if she hates dinosaurs?
No deal.
[narrator] Mark lives in a cabin
next to his parents' house.
- Hey, Dad.
- Hey, Mark.
How was work?
[father chuckles] I'm tired.
- It's been a busy day.
- [Mark] I bet.
- [mother] Hey, Mark.
- Hey, Mum.
- [mother] Had a good day?
- Yeah, I sure did.
Good boy.
I'm looking forward to Matt's wedding.
Have we heard any more from Matt and Emma?
I think in a few weeks,
you'll be going on the bucks night.
- Yeah, that would be fun.
- [mother] Yeah? Looking forward to that?
- Yeah.
- [mother] Yeah?
- [Cian] Is your brother getting married?
- Mm-hmm.
[father] What about you,
would you like to do that one day?
- Yeah.
- You can find the girl of your dreams.
I think you'd make a great boyfriend.
You're a beautiful person.
- [father chuckles]
- Yeah.
[mother laughs]
[snoring]
[chuckles] Oh, Bella...
[chuckles]
We're just amazed at how far he's come.
It... I mean, it's been
a hell of a long journey.
Mark, in his young age,
he had limited language, meltdowns,
he was destructive.
A lot of our friends
who had children with autism,
um, their marriages broke down,
and, uh, ours was strained too.
And so, I think I need people to know
that you do need to work together,
and you have to work hard,
and I think that
it's now paying dividends.
Sorry. [chuckles]
[shuddering] It gets a bit emotional...
because it has been a hard road,
but we've seen light at the end
of the tunnel.
And we've seen Mark just come so far.
[Cian] How would you describe
your ideal girlfriend?
Clever, intelligent,
energetic, athletic, strong...
brave, grateful.
And she smells good.
[Cian] She smells good.
And perhaps has a...
smell of orange juice,
or... um... or...
flowers.
[Cian] That sounds good.
- Konnichi wa, my name's Kelvin Wong.
- Konnichi wa.
Good to see you.
I'm having Teppanyaki here for dinner
with my date.
All right, okay, just take a seat.
- Arigato gozaimasu.
- [man] Dou itashimashite.
[narrator] Kelvin is meeting Jessica.
Jessica likes...
video games...
[video game sounds]
...and cat videos.
[keyboard clacking]
She hates alcohol...
and the song "Happy Birthday."
♪ Happy birthday to you... ♪
[Kelvin] Nobody likes a dumb-dumb man.
Don't be a dumb-dumb-dumb-dumb-dumb-
dumb-dumb-dumb-dumb-dumb...
[Cian] There she is.
My name's Kelvin Wong.
- Hi, Kelvin.
- Nice to meet you.
- What's your name?
- [Jessica] I'm Jessica.
Nice to meet you.
Here...
Please sit down.
[Jessica] Thanks, man.
Wait, that's...
[Kelvin] Mmm, hmm.
You smell good.
Yeah, it does.
Okay.
All right.
What are your interests?
Oh, uh, I like video games
and, uh, computer.
I actually brought my Switch today,
if you want to play Smash.
Um...
When?
No, as in, while we wait
for the server to come over.
I hate waiting. You hate waiting?
What, wait, um...
I am... I am waiting patiently.
- Um, okay.
- Damn, this is...
What about anime?
- Or manga?
- Oh, I don't really...
read or watch much anime,
but I do prefer video games.
I'm just gonna switch this on for you.
Oh, excuse me, any... you like movies?
Oh, uh, I do like to go see movies
from time to time.
So...
do you like animals?
Oh, I... I like animals.
Ooh.
All right, just hold your controller
sideways like this.
All right. Thank you.
And do you like cooking?
Uh, no, I'm not a huge fan of cooking.
Wait a minute... Ah...
I know how to do... what?
What? I lose.
- [Jessica chuckles]
- [Kelvin] Well...
- [Kelvin] Aw.
- Oh, you...
I guess you're not very good
at this game, huh?
You can't really rejoin. Sorry about that.
Sorry, it's a shame.
Shame, it's... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I thought it'd be good
to entertain ourselves.
What?
I thought it'd be good for us
to entertain ourselves.
What?
[Jessica] Hello.
- Hello, how are you?
- [Kelvin] Okay. All right.
[chef] So, tonight we're gonna try
some prawn...
- [Kelvin] Ooh.
- ...fish, chicken...
beef, and fried rice.
All right! Yummy!
So, now I cook the seafood first.
Ooh, fish!
Ooh.
- Cutting up prawn.
- [chef] Yes.
I did read that you had to cut out
the head from the prawn
when you cook them.
Didn't think
you'd have to cut out the guts, too.
- Ooh.
- [Kelvin] Ooh!
- [chef] Thank you.
- Ah, wow.
- You're so smart!
- [chef] Thank you.
- All right, please try prawn first.
- Thank you.
- [Jessica] I will burn myself.
- Kono ebi wa etsui desu.
Hai. Ebisu.
Itadakimasu.
Yeah, what he said. Bon appétit.
Bon appétit!
Yummy.
[child exclaims]
Mmm. Not half bad.
[chef] And we make a fire...
[Jessica] Fire?
Ready?
One, two, three, go!
[Kelvin] Oh!
Hoo, Jesus Christ!
- It is a fire.
- Fire, yeah.
Arigato gozaimasu.
[chef speaking Japanese]
Kelvin, you've been speaking
a lot of Japanese.
Yes, I've been speaking Japanese
for three years.
[chef] And now, we get to play games,
all right?
Can you catch your bowl first?
- Two hands. Yeah.
- Oh, wait a minute.
One, two, three...
Catch! Good, yes.
Oh, I-I learned it
from my teacher, Travis-san.
Ah, nice!
- Every Wednesday or Friday.
- [man] Kelvin, you want to try?
- Yes.
- Two hands on the bowl.
- Good. Yes.
- Yes.
All right, ready?
Catch, all right? One, two, three...
- Catch! Good.
- All right.
- [chef] You got it?
- Yeah.
- [chef] There's your rice.
- [Jessica] Thank you.
How do you make eating with chopsticks
so easy?
I'm a Chinese boy.
And I come from a Chinese family.
- Oh.
- But I was born here in Australia.
[Jessica] I hope you don't mind me
making a mess.
I'm just trying to get used to these.
How do you make them work
so well for you, Kelvin?
What is it?
What is it you're talking about?
- The chopsticks.
- The chopsticks, oh.
Copy me.
No, not like that.
Oh, yeah.
Use your thumb in front of the chopsticks,
only the thumb.
[Jessica] Oh.
- [Kelvin] Mm-hmm. Yeah.
- Oh, thank you.
[Kelvin] Oh...
Um...
You're welcome.
So...
Do you like koalas?
I do like 'em.
And one day,
would you like to go
to the koala park with me?
I would like...
I actually would like that.
How about Taronga Zoo?
Where, Taronga Zoo?
- [Jessica] Mm-hmm.
- That's a...
It's in Mosman.
[siren wailing]
[Kelvin]
Have you seen the ambulance out there?
What are they doing?
I don't know, but it can't be good.
I just hope they aren't coming in here,
though.
Excuse me,
I have to go to the bathroom, please.
Can I go to bathroom, please?
I'll be right back.
Oh, okay.
[Kelvin] Thank you.
Be back.
[Cian] What do you think of Kelvin, Jess?
He's actually pretty nice, if you ask me.
But he often had issues
trying to understand me,
and vice versa.
Maybe it's
because I'm not good at rolling my...
[rolls tongue]
R's, I can't do it.
Cian, uh,
Jessica's a very nice girl to me.
She likes video games,
movies, and traveling.
And... But she doesn't like anime.
- [Jessica] That's not true.
- Or manga.
I actually do like anime,
I just like video games more.
[Cian] Why don't you go join her again
and we can talk later, okay?
[Kelvin] Okay.
Anything you like most,
other than video games?
Oh, I like using the computer.
- Using the "competter"?
- Yeah.
What?
Using the "competter"?
"Competter"?
The computer?
I'm sorry, I don't want to be racist
or anything.
What, what?
As in, you know, you said "competter."
What? I don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm not trying to be mean
or anything, but...
Competter?
I'm sorry, but I meant computer.
You know, laptop?
The laptop.
- PC?
- Like my daddy uses.
- At home.
- Oh, heads up.
All right, ice cream.
Oh, caramel.
- Enjoy.
- Arigato gozaimasu.
Dou itashimashite.
[cheering]
Damn, that is good ice cream.
- You like yours?
- [Kelvin] Mmm, I like this.
It was great going out
on our first date together.
Yeah, but don't automatically think
we're gonna start kissing right now.
Oh, oh, fine.
Like, you're a great guy and all, but...
[slight chuckle]
- I'm not ready to fall in love yet.
- You don't think I'm a g...
You don't think I'm a great guy?
No, I don't think... I don't think...
You're not a bad person or anything.
You don't feel like loving me?
You know what?
You're actually a great person.
I'd actually like to hang out with you
more as a friend.
Not in the romantic way, just in the...
platonic way.
- Platonic?
- Yeah.
So, can I...
- add you to my contacts?
- Okay.
- And what's your phone number?
- [Jessica] I'll just show it to you.
Oh, that's fine.
[Jessica] Just type this.
So, it's been a great time
going on a date together.
Yes. Hopefully, I'll get to catch up
with you sometime soon enough.
Okay, see you!
- Bye, Kelvin!
- Bye, bye!
[Jessica] Like, he's a really nice guy.
I bet he'll find someone
who loves him for who he is.
But he kind of sucks at video games.
She doesn't like manga or anime so much,
but she likes video gaming more than that.
It's better to be friends
than being an official girlfriend.
[Cian] What does love mean for you, Maddi?
Well...
love should mean that you stand by
the person you're in love with,
through thick and thin,
and you don't bail...
just 'cause you're bored.
And it means, like, supporting them,
and not just...
not just turning a blind eye
to when they clearly need help, so...
- [Cian] When are you happiest?
- With family.
Family is like, um, brownies.
They're a really sweet bunch,
but you can't avoid getting a few nuts.
[chuckles]
Right! [claps hands]
Are we ready to get ready for the date?
Yes, let's go get ready.
[narrator] After Maddi didn't feel
any chemistry with Mark,
today she's preparing to meet someone new.
- Here are the pants.
- Uh-huh.
Good.
[Maddi] Here's the shirt.
- Remembering that that goes to the back.
- Yes.
People on the spectrum,
they don't read the social cues
that we all read.
They get a lot of their social cues
off television.
And it was very early on I realized
that I had to be the one
she was getting her social cues off.
- Hey. How's it going?
- Oh!
Oh, come around. Show me, show me,
show me, show me, show me.
Oh, that's good.
Okay, how you feeling about it all?
A tad nervous, but... [chuckles]
Do you wanna go through a rehearsal?
- Yeah, good idea.
- Steve, you're the barman.
- What are you gonna do when you meet him?
- Hi, nice to meet you, I'm Maddi.
Oh, hi, Mad...
Maddi, you don't need to...
- What?
- That's very hard.
You've got a weak handshake
'cause you're old.
Okay. Lovely to meet you, Maddi.
- Can I get you a drink?
- A lemonade, please.
- Lemonade.
- A lemonade, too. Thank you, barman.
Two lemonades.
So, you look lovely.
Oh, thank you, you look decent as well.
You look decent? [laughs]
[Maddi] It depends
on what his outfit looks like.
What do you do for a living?
I'm a jewelry designer.
- Yes.
- That job must rock.
That's a good one! That's a good one!
[laughter]
- Your table is ready.
- Thank you.
- Maddison, would you like to go to dinner?
- Yes.
Sit there, I'll sit over here with Steve.
So, the idea
is to keep the conversation flowing.
Do you have any siblings?
Uh, I have two sisters and two brothers.
What about you?
Two brothers and two sisters.
And I have six nephews and lots of nieces.
So, that's a lot of nieces and nephews...
- Do you want children of your own?
- No, never.
When you're answer is no,
you leave nowhere for the person to go.
Because what you're trying to do
is keep the conversation going.
Let's try again.
Do you want children of your own?
No, because I think
they're a waste of time and money.
Good lord.
- [Terri laughs]
- [father] What is that smile?
- I don't know.
- What is that smile?
- Am I not allowed to smile?
- [Terri] No, people like smiles.
- Just be yourself, gorgeous.
- Just relax.
You're telling me
to keep the conversation going,
but telling me not to tell people
what they wanna hear,
so I don't know how to combine those two.
You can. You can still be honest,
and... and say,
"Look, I don't think
I'm ready for children.
I may never be ready for children."
It just leaves it open.
"I may never"? I don't want to, like,
put any maybe in there,
in case he, like... I give him false hope.
I don't want to, like, not prepare for it,
and it comes up
and I don't know what to do, so...
cover everything.
The chances of something coming up
that we haven't covered is pretty high.
We're gonna need to sit here
for ages, then.
- No, we're not.
- [Maddi] Yes, we are.
You can't send me out there
without being prepared.
It is meant to be fun.
Yeah, it is.
Okay.
So exciting, huh?
Yes. [chuckles]
- [Cian] Are you a romantic person, Mark?
- Yes.
Absolutely.
And I just want to share my life
with someone very special,
and just show her the person
that I really am,
and to show her that my disability
is not an obstacle,
that I'm capable of falling in love.
[Cian] If you do find love,
how do you think you'd know?
I feel like my heart skips a beat.
My smile begins to beam.
I just feel...
entranced.
[narrator] Today, Mark is going bowling
with a social group
set up for people on the spectrum.
[Mark] The social club is about people
with disabilities coming together,
making friends, and having fun,
which is very important,
not just to me, but to everyone else
that has a disability.
Hi Mark, you came.
Gonna sign up and play?
- Okay, cool.
- Yeah.
How about you, Christina?
- You good?
- [Christina] I'm all right.
You ready to have some fun tonight, guys?
Oh, yes.
Oh... no, no, no!
What do you... What do you think
about the new girls here?
Yeah, they're nice.
They're nice. I might like to talk to them
a bit more later on.
You know, get to know them better.
So, how's your night been so far?
You enjoying yourself?
Yeah! Yeah, it's cool.
- I haven't bowled in ages, but...
- Yeah.
So, do you have any family?
Um...
[chuckles]
Well, yes, I have family.
It's just me and my mum at home.
Okay, I have a brother and a sister,
and I have a mum and dad
at home right now.
And, uh, my sister will be...
expecting soon in May.
Oh, wow.
I... I don't really care
- if it's a boy or a girl...
- [chuckles]
...as long as we're getting
a new little...
little baby child.
Well, that's certainly happening.
- Yes.
- [laughs]
Oh.
Ready to go.
Righto.
[Mark] Good luck, Presley.
Thank... Oh, thank you. [chuckles]
[woman] Oh, that's a good one!
We'll... We'll see.
[Mark] Yes!
- Um, Presley?
- Yes?
What are your interests in?
I'm keen to know, what do you like?
Um, I like to draw.
Oh, that's great.
Yeah, I really enjoy that.
I like drawing nature
- and, like, animals and stuff.
- Oh, that's beautiful.
- Yeah.
- Very beautiful.
What do you like to do?
Play video games, watch movies,
read books.
Yeah. What movies are you into?
Which ones are you into?
Um... [inhales]
Well... [exhales]
Um, just...
Uh, well...
Just...
Sorry, I'm... blanking out.
- Hang on, sorry. Excuse me for a second.
- That's okay. You all right?
[Mark, softly] Oh, God.
Sorry. I just blanked out
from nervousness.
[exhales] I was just talking to her,
and just don't know what to say.
Couldn't talk.
Just... just... just be yourself, man.
Just... just...
And just... ask your questions, you know?
- Just build on those conversations.
- Right.
- [man] You'll do fine.
- [man 2] You're doing great, Mark.
Just breathe.
[Mark] Come on.
[sighs]
[narrator] Armed with her parents'
dating advice,
Maddi is heading out for a dinner date.
She'll be meeting Severin.
Severin likes...
structure and organization...
and violins that can hold a note.
[plays note]
He doesn't like bananas...
[man screams]
...or hairy spiders.
Hi, are you Severin?
Hey. Yeah.
- Maddi, nice to meet you.
- You're Maddi. Yep.
Well, you know, how was your day, I guess.
Oh, yeah, pretty good.
Pretty good, just catching up on...
chores, errands, bits and pieces, so...
- Yeah.
- And your... how was your day?
Um...
Let's see... Well, um...
had an appointment earlier, and...
other than that, um...
- sprucing up a bit. [chuckles]
- Ah.
'Cause, um...
Well, yeah.
Uh, so...
Yeah... So, um...
What do you like to do for fun?
Oh.
Uh, I... I love video games.
I'm a huge video game nerd, so... [laughs]
Nice, same.
What kind of games do you play?
- I play The Sims 4. That's a great game.
- Yep.
- You can create or destroy.
- [chuckles]
- I'm the ruler.
- [Severin] Nice.
- [Maddi] Yeah.
- Um...
So...
Yeah, um...
Um... [exhales]
[exhales]
Yeah.
[both softly grunt]
Um...
- So, um...
- [child screams]
- Goodness me, listen to that noise.
- Wow.
Screaming kids, that is horrible noise.
It's like, be quiet.
- Um...
- [Maddi] Thank God it stopped.
Like, do you think you'd ever
want kids one day? Like...
Oh, it's... It's funny for me.
Like, if you asked me maybe a year ago,
I'd be like, "No, I never want children,
ever! Ever, ever!"
- [laughs]
- Like, that's what I was like,
but I think as I've gotten older,
like, I...
Changed your mind a bit?
Like, I've become more open to the idea.
I don't really know if I'd ever want kids.
I... I'm open to the idea,
like, eventually if I was to find,
like, the right person...
- Hmm, but yeah.
- Yeah, being open-minded, so...
Yeah.
Crumbs, I was afraid this would happen.
It's starting to fall apart.
Oh, whoa.
[Maddi laughing] Oh.
[Severin] Yeah.
Ah...
Oh.
[clears throat]
[waitress] All done, guys?
- [Severin] Oh, yeah.
- Yeah?
- [Severin] Yeah.
- All good? [laughs]
No worries.
How was everything?
- Delicious, thank you.
- [Severin] Yeah, pretty good.
Great. All good.
Um...
May I ask, what do you potentially think
you want to do as a career one day?
I think something with...
something with animals.
- I did an animal studies course at TAFE.
- [Severin] Okay.
Now I'm doing
Cert III Music Industry at TAFE.
- The piano...
- Oh.
...specifically.
- Nice.
- [Severin] Um...
Absolutely love piano
with great burning passion, so...
When I was in high school,
and I heard a guy playing,
I... I think it was actually
the Skyrim theme on piano,
Oh, wow.
That's what sparked a bit of interest.
And then I started,
like, self-teaching myself.
- Wow.
- And um... yeah.
I do have a surprise for you.
Oh. [slight chuckle]
'Cause, did you know,
there's a piano they have right here.
Oh, my goodness.
- I didn't notice that on the way in, no.
- [Severin] Yeah.
You like Skyrim, right?
Yeah...
[plays Skyrim theme]
Oh, I recognize that.
- Wow, like...
- [Severin exhales]
A bit improvisation, a bit...
actual Skyrim.
[Severin] Uh...
Seriously, you are really good at that.
- Yeah.
- Did you have lessons
- when you were younger, or like...?
- No, I've...
- All self-taught?
- I've self...
Well, pretty much, yeah.
I've self-taught since I was 18.
That's very impressive
for self-taught then.
Oh, man.
- Y-You all right?
- [Maddi] Yeah.
Uh, um...
[Severin exhales] So, yeah...
Is it the first date where you said
they played Skyrim for you on the piano?
Yeah, it's the first time
anyone's done that for me.
- So, thank you very much. Very accurate.
- [chuckles]
- But yeah, um...
- [Maddi] All right.
- Well...
- Well, I had a good evening, Severin.
Thank you for coming out here
and doing this. Nice to get to know you.
- Yeah, nice to get to know you, too. Um...
- Yeah.
So, uh, you know...
Do, like...
Uh...
Do you want to do this again
sometime or...
Yeah, it's a good... It's a good idea.
We should... We should do this again.
Fair enough, um...
Okay, um...
- Yeah, I'll call you then.
- All right.
It was nice meeting you.
Nice to meet you, too.
Thanks for coming out, and...
- Yep.
- [Maddi] That's everything, so...
- Bye.
- Have a great night.
- You too, bye.
- [Severin] Yep.
See ya, have a great one.
She seems fairly geeky as well,
which is, you know, my type.
You know, I like someone
who's a bit nerdy, like me.
I think there may be potential there
for something great.
[line trilling]
[Terri] Hey, Maddi.
Hey, how are you guys?
[Terri] Good! How was your date?
Oh, yeah, really good. He was very...
Severin was a very interesting guy.
[Terri] Yeah? Cool!
He played piano for... for me
at the... at the restaurant.
At the pub, so... [laughs]
[Terri] Oh, my Lord! Was he very good?
Oh, he is really good.
You know that game I play, Skyrim?
- [Terri] Yeah.
- [father] Yeah.
He played me a music track on there
which I recognize.
I was like, "Wow, how accurate!"
[Terri] Oh, wow, so you obviously had
a lot more interest in him
than the last guy, right?
Suppose so.
[Terri] Excellent. That sounds like
a very successful night, then.
Yeah.
[Terri] Okay, all right. Well, then, uh,
we'll see you home soon, hey.
Bye, guys. See you later. Bye.
- [Cian] They sound happy.
- Yeah.
[zips purse]
They always insist
on being part of my life, so... [laughs]
As parents do, I suppose.
[laughs]
Yeah.
[Cian] What do you think's the biggest
challenge you've had to overcome?
Um... [exhales]
Trying to work on my social skills, and...
trying to...
you know...
see how the real world works,
and stuff like that.
It's been a huge challenge.
[birds chirping]
- Can't wait for today's activities.
- It's a good opportunity, too, darling.
Oh, yes.
[narrator] Today, Mark is attending
a dating workshop,
hoping to learn skills that will help him
in his search for love.
- Have a great day.
- Well, you too.
Hope you learn a lot...
- I will.
- And get a lot out of today.
- See ya, Dad.
- See ya, mate.
[narrator] Dr. Elizabeth Laugeson
is the director of PEERS,
a social skills training program
for people on the autism spectrum,
developed at the University of California.
One of the biggest misconceptions
that I've found
about people on the spectrum
is that they're perfectly happy
not being social, not dating,
and that just really is very rarely true.
You guys excited for today?
[all] Yes.
[Elizabeth] For years, my phone
has just been ringing off the hook
from adults and their family members,
um, desperate to learn
how to develop romantic relationships.
So that's where we come in
with our dating boot camps,
is to try to teach the skills
that many people sort of take for granted
and use naturally in dating situations.
Dating is a choice, right?
Do we get to date everybody?
No.
No. Does everyone get to date us?
What could be the problem with choosing
someone who's maybe not so nice?
- They could be doing drugs or alcohol.
- [Elizabeth] Yeah.
- They could be part of a gang or...
Would that be a good choice
in someone to date?
- No.
- So we're all clear,
there's good choices and bad choices
when it comes to dating, right?
[birds chirping]
When we're on a date,
we have to be able
to make conversation with people.
Remember, we're supposed
to trade information.
Well, there's lots of rules
about trading information.
So one of the things you do
is you're gonna ask questions, right?
Because what is the goal,
what are you trying to find?
[man] Find common interests.
Exactly. And so,
in order to find common interests,
you have to share things
about yourself as well.
Yes.
[Elizabeth] Okay, we're gonna see
a few role-plays about what not to do.
So I want you guys
to watch this role-play,
and I want you to notice
what Nathan is doing wrong
in trying to trade information.
-So, Lizzie, what'd you do on the weekend?
- I just went to the beach.
- Oh, cool, which beach?
- Uh, Bronte.
- Oh, did you go with your friends?
- Yeah, a couple friends.
- Did you go swimming or surfing?
- Uh, swimming.
- Oh, do you build sandcastles?
- [laughs]
- [Nathan] Do you play beach volleyball?
[Elizabeth] All right, timeout.
So what did Nathan do wrong, Joseph?
Um, ask too many questions.
He was being an interviewer, right?
It's not a reciprocal conversation,
so they're not finding common interests.
It has to go back and forth.
Okay, watch this next role-play.
Think about what Nathan is doing wrong
this time.
So, Lizzie, who was the last person
you dated?
[Lizzie] Uh... Jason.
Did you love him?
- [Lizzie] Uh... Yeah.
- [Nathan] What about me?
Do you love me?
Uh, sorry. Could we order dinner first?
When are we gonna go on our honeymoon?
- [Lizzie] I'm just not... Sorry.
- [Nathan] When should we get married?
[Elizabeth] Okay, timeout.
So what did Nathan do wrong?
A little bit too personal.
He was getting too personal.
Yeah, what else? Mark?
It was like this.
He put the hammer down too soon, you know?
Got right into it way too quickly.
Yeah, right, kinda came on way too strong.
Joseph?
Was being a bit too imposing
and getting down her throat a bit.
Yeah, exactly.
All right, guys. Well, now that we know
how to trade information
and hopefully make conversations
during dates,
we're gonna practice this.
So, who wants to go first?
Okay, Mark, wonderful. Come on up
to the front of the room here with Lizzie.
We're gonna imagine
that you're on a date with Lizzie,
- and you're just making conversation.
- [Mark] Yeah.
And what will your goal be
in this conversation?
- To find common interests.
- [Elizabeth] Very good. All right.
So, what do you like to get up to
on weekends?
I kinda like playing tennis
and things like that.
- Oh, yes.
- Swimming, yeah...
- Well, my mum plays tennis.
- Oh cool, nice.
She used to be in the...
the league, but...
She doesn't anymore.
You know, so she just does it
in her spare time.
Yeah. That sounds fun. Have you tried it?
I have, but I'm a little bit sloppy at it.
- Keep missing it, it's just...
- [laughs]
[laughs]
I just...
Um, just...
Um, just trying to think...
Sorry, I'm... Oh.
So, don't worry about that.
You're doing a fantastic job.
But think about questions
that you might ask the other person...
- Oh, yes.
- ...to sort of get out their interests.
And then you're doing a good job
of sharing about yourself,
but always making sure
you're also checking in with Lizzie.
Question, do you ever find it difficult
to sort of come up
with new topics to talk about?
- Yes.
- [Elizabeth] Yeah. Does...
Does that happen to other people too?
- [woman] Yep.
- [Elizabeth] Yeah.
So, you know what?
This is a great opportunity
for all of us as a group
to maybe brainstorm
what are some common topics
that people talk about on dates?
[man] Family.
Family, exactly. What else?
- Holidays?
- [Elizabeth] Holidays!
[Elizabeth] A lot of people think
that social skills are abstract,
but in reality, we're all naturally
following concrete rules and steps,
and so it's really critical
that we outline
what these steps are for our young adults.
What else do you like to do?
Go hiking, or to the beach,
or see my friends...
- What about you?
- Well...
[inhales] I like to...
to go hiking as well.
- I love to get out in nature.
- [Lizzie] You do?
Yeah, it's so much fun.
It makes me feel peace
whenever I'm in nature.
- Wouldn't you agree?
- Yeah. Yeah, I totally agree. Yeah.
I got lost last time I went.
- [laughs]
- Oh.
- Well, I know my way around the forest.
- Oh, that's good, yeah. [laughs]
- It's a very good skill to have. Yeah.
- Yeah.
I think Mark did a great job.
What do you guys think?
I think he did awesome.
- Shall we give him a round of applause?
- Yes. Thank you.
- [Elizabeth] That was fantastic.
- [applause]
[Kelvin] Well done, Mark.
Thank you, thanks.
Thank you.
[birds chirping]
Okay, well, it's just been such a pleasure
working with all of you.
I'm so, so, proud of all of the...
the progress I just saw in one day.
I just want to wish you all
the best of luck in dating.
You know, dating can be hard, for anybody.
But now you guys have all the tools
that you need,
and it'll be a whole new experience
for you moving forward.
I wish you guys
the very, very best of luck,
and a big round of applause to all of you.
- Congratulations...
- [applause]
...on completing our boot camp.
[wind chime jingling]
Can you feel those?
Do you think they look cold enough?
Perfect, yeah.
[narrator] Armed with the skills
he learned at boot camp,
Mark is getting ready
for a date at the zoo.
[Cian] What are your hopes for today?
I hope we enjoy each other's company
- and we have a good time.
- Yeah.
Just be your adorable, beautiful self.
- [chuckles] Thanks.
- And...
pay attention to what she's interested in.
- Tell here about yourself.
- I will.
Sometimes girls like to talk
about themselves, too...
- Yeah.
- ...a little bit.
I know. I know.
I've got one tip for you, Mark.
You know how you've been going to the gym?
You want her to see your muscles,
so this is how you do it, just like...
You go like this, and you go,
"Do you see the pelicans over there?"
- And let her see it, okay?
- What do you think of that?
- She'll be impressed.
- What do you think of that tip?
- I know, I know.
- [laughs]
Just let me handle it my way.
- Yeah, thanks, Dad.
- Yes.
[laughs] Thanks for nothing.
Yeah, thanks.... Thanks.
- So happy for him.
- Ah, it'll be great, won't it?
Bye, sweet.
Subtitles Diego Moraes(oakislandtk)
www.opensubtitles.org