- [man] What do you think love is?
- It'll be like a fairy tale.
A natural high, I suppose?
Gets your heart racing.
Can make people do crazy things.
You just feel very warm inside yourself
as a person.
- [man] So, have you ever been in love?
- No.
- [man] Have you been in a relationship?
- [man] Have you been on a date?
- No.
[narrator] Finding love
can be hard for anyone.
[sighs]
That was too awkward.
[narrator] And for some people,
it can feel like an impossible dream.
Some girls don't feel like dating
with someone with disabilities.
Beep, beep, bi, boop.
[narrator] This series follows
young adults on the autism spectrum...
An A-plus partner looks like me.
- [laughs]
- [narrator] ...as they navigate
the confusing world
- of relationships and dating.
- Oh!
Would you like to get married?
Um...
"The course of true love
never did run smooth."
Of course it doesn't.
- [man] You ready?
- Yes, ready. [clears throat]
Hello.
My name is Michael,
and I happen to be a 25-year-old man.
[man] How do you feel
about being on the spectrum?
Well, autism is just
a neurological disability.
People with Asperger's or autism,
they just learn things a different way.
As far as I'm concerned,
if anything, it's actually more of a gift.
[man] And are you looking for love,
Michael?
Oh, yes, I am.
I would like to start dating.
I just, um...
don't really know how to get started,
because...
I've tried numerous ways,
and they've all been unsuccessful.
[man] What's your greatest dream in life?
To become a husband.
[birds chirping]
[narrator] People on the spectrum
often have trouble socializing,
and meeting potential partners
can be difficult.
This room here is my bedroom,
but I actually call it my quarters.
It's the main place in this world
that I feel safe.
These are my love ducks.
If you are single and seeking love,
sit them beside your bed
and love is sure to come your way.
I actually bought them from a store
in Newtown six years ago.
Excuse me a second, gentlemen.
- [man] Oh, what is that?
- [Michael] It's a plaque.
I actually made it specifically
for my future wife.
- [man] When did you make this?
- [Michael] Five years ago.
[man] Wow, you really want this, Michael!
Oh, yes, I do.
It's most important thing
that I want to achieve.
[man] Well, I hope we can help you
achieve that.
[Michael] I really hope so, too.
I seriously do.
[narrator] Later this week,
with help from the filmmakers,
Michael will have
his first dating experience
at a singles dinner.
I often compare myself to Adam,
my brother, a lot,
which is a big mistake.
I would often label him
as a fresh cut of meat from God,
and myself as a double scoop of dog shit.
Why on earth he wanted to compare himself
to me, I don't know, but...
It's because I've often felt inferior
to my brother.
Adam was able to get himself
in a relationship easily,
whereas I had trouble doing so.
The challenges that you face, Mike,
I think a lot of other people face, too.
To struggle at some point or another
to find, like, proper love.
But for some strange reason,
I don't seem to recall Adam
having any problems like that.
[father] Because we're all different.
But Michael, you've seen
over the past few years,
how it just hasn't worked out for me
either. Like, it just turns to shit.
That's also because a lot of people
our age aren't interested in commitment.
They're only interested in intercourse.
[laughter]
Yeah. Look, it's true.
[father] Oops.
- Dad, did you drop your food?
- [father] Yeah.
And also... I've also... What I've also
noticed with a lot of girls your age, Liv,
when they're still in high school,
they only want a boyfriend for...
- Intercourse.
- Not just... Not just for intercourse,
but also as a bodyguard
and as a sugar daddy.
[laughter]
I think every family needs a Michael.
It just adds something different.
[laughs]
[chuckling softly]
Hi, I'm Chloe. I'm 19, and I'm autistic.
I was born, well, not completely deaf,
but never been able to hear fully.
I have hearing aids,
it's nothing to be ashamed of.
[man] Have you ever been in love?
N... [sighs]
Not romantic love.
I don't know what it's like
to fall in love or have a crush.
- [man] So, have you ever dated?
- Yes, I have.
I once dated a guy who, when I told him
that I was autistic, he left me,
because he didn't want to be associated
with someone who's autistic.
[man] How did that make you feel?
Well, I was a bit... angry,
or I was confused.
I was like, is autism really bad?
- [man] And you accept your autism?
- Yes, I do.
Took me a while, but I do, yes.
When I tell someone I'm autistic,
people go, "Really? No, you're not.
You don't look autistic."
And I can say, "What does
an autistic person look like?"
[narrator] Chloe was 11
when she was diagnosed with autism.
In the past, girls were four times
less likely than boys to be diagnosed.
But that number is steadily increasing
as we learn more
about the presentation of autism in girls.
I want to experience love.
I want to be like everyone else, you know?
I just don't want to be alone
for the rest of my life.
I see so many people holding hands
and kissing and doing all that,
and that's something I want.
I had, like, all these ideas in my head,
and none of them happened.
Life is not a movie.
[dog barking]
What's up, man? Come here.
[father] When you start doing
the whole dating thing,
that fairy-tale thing,
- it's gonna take a while to get to that.
- Yeah, I know.
So, you know, don't expect that
as the first one,
because it's not an easy situation
to get into.
I'd like someone who I can talk to
about Marvel, or, you know...
- Exactly.
- ...new cartoons and animes coming out.
So, I'll go and crack on
and start doing some dinner stuff.
Remember, not touching.
It won't be touching, Chloe.
It won't be touching, I promise.
I'm very picky when it comes...
I don't like things touching other things.
The beans have to be separated.
Like, a little bit of beans on the side,
they can't touch.
All right, let them start warming.
She's a really intelligent girl.
She's, you know, incredibly intelligent,
but socially, she's not.
She's often had a lot of problems
with difficulties reading
someone's emotions.
It's a lot harder to make a friendship.
So, to move onto anything intimate,
I think it would be a huge challenge.
From the little girl that couldn't say
any words to me,
to the day she said "daddy"
for the first time,
to where she is now, yeah,
I'm hugely proud of where she's come from.
She's... She's done fantastically.
She's, um... yeah.
After everything she's had against her.
[inhales deeply]
- Yep, sorry. [chuckles]
- [man] No, you're all right.
Yeah, no, she's done really well.
I used to get bullied quite a lot
in school in England for how I look.
I got called names, I got pushed,
I had, you know, my work ripped up,
and called me deaf,
and then I got called "skeleton."
I think, you know, being bullied
has made me who I am,
and if I wasn't bullied, I would've been
someone completely different.
[narrator] Chloe's best friend Brodie
lives nearby.
They catch up socially
several times a week.
Do you want milkshake or tea?
- A tea.
- A tea?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
What do you want?
I don't know. Same as you.
- Yeah.
[Chloe] My friend Brodie
has Down's syndrome,
and she's mute and deaf,
but she signs, and I sign a lot,
and we're like this.
You know, can't separate us.
And we cause... We get told
we cause a lot of trouble, and...
You know, we just don't follow the rules.
Oh, look, Brodie, boy!
- You like him?
- [laughs]
[Chloe laughs]
You gonna talk to the boys?
Come on.
Come on, talk to the boys.
No, you! You!
- Hey.
- [Chloe laughs]
- Want to talk?
- [Brodie exclaims]
[Chloe laughs]
Hello.
- Come here.
- [Chloe laughing]
[speaking indistinctly]
I don't know their names. [laughs]
[Chloe laughs]
Cheeky.
- You're cheeky.
- No, you're cheeky.
[Chloe laughs]
[both laughing]
A lot of things happen
when me and Brodie go out. [laughs]
I just think she's this amazing person,
and she's absolutely amazing to be around.
I just find it sad
that some people just look at her
for, you know, what she looks like,
and just, uh... you know, judges her.
Yeah, you're cheeky.
[Chloe laughing]
Hello.
Um, my name is Ruth Garlick,
and, uh, I'm 22 years old,
and, um...
I'm primarily a deaf autistic.
[man] And who's this?
What's this?
Oh, this is my baby snake Cleopatra.
She helps me to stay calm.
And it means I don't have
a lot of sensory overload
when I'm handling her.
[man] Can you describe your ideal partner?
Oh, sure, um...
My ideal... ideal partner
would be a blondie
who's a big cuddler.
He also needs to be able
to be okay with my quirks
and my nerdiness.
He's just over there. Come along.
- Hey, gorgeous.
- Hello.
I'm Thomas.
We've been, um, dating for...
about four years now,
and I think we do all right together.
[man] Thomas, what do you love about Ruth?
She's funny, fun to be with, um...
r-really smart...
a-a-a killer body,
and just puts up with me.
Yeah, he loves my body,
that's why he stays with me.
I... I really do. It's sexy.
- [laughs]
- Sexy.
I think we do work well together.
I'm autistic enough to understand Ruth,
and she can understand me back.
Likening it to curry,
she's a very spicy chicken tikka masala,
but I'm... I'm a nice...
nice mild, um, butter chick...
No, I'm a... I'm a mango chicken.
I've decided I want to be a mango chicken.
Yeah, so basically, I'm fire,
and he's water.
And together, fire and water,
things get steamy.
[laughs] That's true.
[laughs]
That's very naughty.
Yes, it is.
[narrator] For Ruth and Thomas,
finding love has led to independence.
They moved in together
just over a year ago.
[Ruth] This is my card collection.
This here's thick.
So it's quite heavy.
This is one of my favorite sections,
which is food.
- [man] So you collect business cards?
- [Ruth] Yes, I do.
[man] What's your guess
at how many you have?
How many? Um, probably thousands.
Look, there's...
This is a lot.
I can't wait to sort them all out.
[man] I don't think I've ever met anyone
who collects business cards.
Well, autistic people are known
for being pretty unusual.
[grunts]
[Thomas] This is my garden railway.
[train whistling]
A garden is your own idea of heaven.
So, of course, mine's gonna have
a train running through it.
[man] When did you guys first meet?
My sister told me that, um,
she knew another aspie at church,
and, uh, she wanted me to meet him,
because she thought
we'd become friends.
We immediately understood each other.
We... And I actually...
When we first met each other,
I wrote in my journal,
- "Oh, I want to marry this guy."
- [laughs]
I didn't know that.
That's true. I told you that before.
[man] Likes her milk.
That's why I need to go buy some.
[man] What's that picture on the fridge?
- That one?
- [man] Hmm.
Ruth drew that for my birthday.
"Happy birthday, Tom,
from your crazy girlfriend Ruthy."
And then that is, um, runes.
[Ruth] Can't wait to marry you.
I love you, Ruth.
Apparently, it says that.
If I actually was dating somebody,
and I actually entered a relationship,
and then eventually...
married her,
I would treat her as my top priority.
She would be pretty much my most valuable
and greatest treasure of all time.
She'd practically be my million dollars.
- [mother] Mike, can you get me some salt?
- [Michael] Yeah.
- You mean the sea salt?
- Yep. Please.
[man] Why do you think Michael's
finding it hard to meet someone?
I think he just needs to find somebody
that's like-minded.
I don't think he wants anybody loud.
Or gothic.
- Mm-hmm.
- [Michael] Or tomboyish.
Mm-hmm.
Or practically any girl that acts like...
like she's still in high school.
Yeah. Sounds right.
If she's the right person for me, then...
I'll... I'll consider proposing to her.
- Okay.
- By coincidence, I've already decided
on the perfect wedding ring
for my partner.
In the form of a crown...
to signify that she'll be my queen,
per se.
But I'm not really too keen on kids
at the moment, because... [inhales]
I have a feeling that having children
will ruin my chances of becoming wealthy.
They kinda do. [laughs]
But what if you meet a girl
that wants to have children,
and you're like,
"Oh, but that's gonna take away
from my bank account."
What are you gonna do?
I'll simply tell her, "Okay,
I'll allow it, but on one condition.
I get a vasectomy after the second child."
Okay.
I've been single for 25 years.
I'm not too willing to be single
for another 25.
What if you are?
Mum.
I still refuse to take that for an answer.
But it's not an answer. I'm just saying,
it's a hypothetical what-if.
Not what if. It will.
Okay. That's it.
[mother] It will. Okay.
It will. [laughs]
[narrator] To help him
in his search for love,
Michael is meeting Jodi Rogers,
a relationship specialist
who works with people on the spectrum.
[Jodi] When they're children,
there's a lot of support
given to people with autism
about social skill and social interaction.
And I think when people reach adulthood,
and they're really looking
for intimate relationships,
I think that we don't give
a lot of support to understanding
- the really great complexity...
- [knocking]
...of flirting with somebody else,
or how do we develop an intimate
relationship with somebody else?
- Hello.
- [Jodi] Hello.
You must be Jodi.
- [Jodi] Yes, hello. Are you Michael?
- Yes, I am.
[Jodi] Where do people meet each other
when they're on the autism spectrum?
People go onto sort of
a mainstream dating site,
and then do you out yourself
as being on the spectrum,
which is really complex?
[Michael] I've never had a partner before.
I've always had some trouble
trying to find a partner.
Why do you think that is?
Well, a lot of girls
that I've been friends with in the past,
a... a lot of those friendships
have turned out to be quite... [inhales]
disappointing.
Do you have trouble with understanding
another person's body language?
I have very little trouble.
Facial expressions
always give something away.
That's great.
It's excellent that you say that.
Because some people on the spectrum,
they really have difficulty with that.
So that's excellent
- that you've got that ability to do that.
- Yeah. Yes.
When I'm with somebody,
if they're trying to mask...
mask something...
- [mother] He knows.
- ...on their face,
I'll just simply say,
mask it all you want,
but I know what you're actually feeling.
- [mother] Yes!
- Really?
He... And you know what,
he's so good at it.
He's so... Even with people he's just met.
I've been studying human behavior
for many years.
That's excellent, Michael.
- Specifically in women.
- Yeah.
- [laughs]
- Oh.
It's because I've always taken
a bit of an interest in it,
in a... in a strange way.
No, that's not strange. Do you know what,
if you're on the autism spectrum,
and you find body language difficult,
actually studying body language
is a really important thing to do.
I was told that nonverbal cues,
he'll never be able to get.
Excuse me, nonverbal cues?
Look at his gift.
I was told, "Oh, you know,
you'll... you'll probably never
hear him say I love you."
They said he probably won't have
any empathy for others.
Biggest bunch of rubbish I ever heard.
It's just a difference
in the way that they do things.
They're just different, that's it.
And people with autism
have incredible affection...
- [mother] Yes.
- ...and deep love.
- Yes!
- [Jodi] Really wanting to connect.
When people talk to Michael,
they might find him a bit of an oddball,
a bit quirky, and stuff like that.
But the thing is, we've raised him
and taught him... [inhales]
to be confident with himself,
and that, you know what?
Even as so-called "normal people,"
we don't have all the answers.
But you two have obviously done
a really, really fantastic job as parents.
They haven't given me everything.
Not everything, but plenty.
- [parents laugh]
- Which is still adequate.
Which is still adequate?
- [Michael] Yes.
- [Jodi] Yep.
What's the difference between...
friendship and a girlfriend?
Girlfriends, they're more serious,
it's more intimate,
and there's no hands-to-yourself business.
- [parents laugh]
- Okay, hang on, hang on.
- So, it's more...
- Because that's...
[Jodi] Tell me the difference.
It's more serious...
What do you mean by more serious?
- [Michael] When I say serious...
- [Jodi] Yeah.
- ...you make the decision to...
- Yeah.
- [father laughing]
- ...to kiss each other or, um...
We don't talk to Mum and Dad
about kissing,
- do we?
- [mother] No.
[sighs] N-Not... Not really.
- I never really thought about that.
- [laughter]
Because, you see, I've never...
never had any interest in having...
in having sexual intercourse as...
if you will. Um...
- Okay, this is where I exit. [laughs]
- [Jodi] Yeah.
I have to say,
that could be a good time. [laughs]
Thanks very much for coming.
We'll leave you guys to it.
And, like, one of my philosophies is,
never fall for a girl
just because she's hot.
I think that's an excellent philosophy.
- I made that up myself.
- Did you?
[laughs]
It's a good... It's a very good one.
So, when we're going on a first date,
what we're doing
is we're trying to find out
have we got enough things in...
- ...common.
What would be one thing
that you can think of
if you could make a girlfriend,
what would be something that you're into
and that she's into?
[Michael] There is a hobby
that I enjoy doing.
I actually tend to do this one in secret.
That's toy collecting.
[Jodi] If you don't have
enough things in common,
what do we do?
Not bother with another date.
We don't just give up, we keep going,
- because we just have to keep finding...
- Yeah.
...that person that's gonna be your person
- with enough in common with you.
- Yeah.
I'd really like for you to let me know
how you go on your dates,
and especially to find out
if you've been able to find somebody
- that you have common interest with.
- Okay.
- It was lovely to meet you.
- Like... Likewise.
Take care of yourself.
- See ya.
- And good luck.
Thanks. Thanks for your time.
[man] Are you open to dating people
who might have a disability
or a condition?
Oh, yes.
And I think dating someone
who's on the autistic spectrum,
or someone, you know, with disabilities
might be better.
I might... I might have, um...
be able to talk to them more about it
and not feel like I have to be fake
and be someone completely different.
[narrator] It's been almost two years
since Chloe has been on a date,
but that's about to change.
Hello.
- [father] Hello, miss.
- Yeah.
If you need to, just, you know,
twiddle your fingers or something,
if you're getting a little bit nervy.
And you can always excuse yourself,
you need to powder your nose or something.
Okay, but I don't have nose powder.
No, no. It's... It's a saying, isn't it.
- You go for... go for a wee.
- [Chloe] Oh, okay.
But it's not honest.
[father] That's true. Maybe you could say,
- I'm just gonna just pop to the bathroom.
- [Chloe] Okay.
And you can have a little bit of time.
- Okay.
- All right?
Just... Just ask him what he likes, and...
boom, if there's a connection,
it's a connection.
[chuckles] Hmm.
[narrator] Chloe is meeting Marcus.
He likes playing drums...
and watching sunsets.
[bird squawks]
- He hates thunderstorms...
- [thunder crashes]
...and the feeling of thongs
between his toes.
[rubber squeaking]
- Hello.
- [Marcus] Hello.
I'm Chloe.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you, too.
Here you go.
Oh, thank you so much. They're lovely.
- Thank you.
- [Marcus] Thank you.
So, how are you?
I'm pretty good.
[Chloe] Yeah?
You nervous?
- Yeah, I am.
- [laughs]
What do you like?
Do you have any hobbies?
I like to go to, um...
- to the gym.
- [Chloe] Oh, gym?
To be honest,
I have never set foot in a gym.
- Mmm.
- [laughing] Never. Not my thing.
Yeah. So, do you like reading?
Like, do you know any good books?
I do read sometimes, but not a lot...
- Yeah.
- ...because, um...
Well, actually, I didn't learn
how to fully read until I was 13.
- [Chloe] Oh, really?
- Yeah.
[Chloe] I couldn't speak
until I was seven.
I still have a lisp, but I'm deaf, so...
Oh, okay.
Autistic, deaf.
- Yeah.
- [Chloe laughing] Yeah.
Can't speak properly.
Yeah, the whole package, I guess.
[Chloe chuckles]
Um...
- Do you want to go inside for dinner?
- Yeah, sure.
Okay.
Oh, she's pretty cool.
You know, it's going pretty well so far.
I hope it can...
only go up from here, you know?
- [chuckles]
- [grunts]
So, have you ever, like, dated before?
Never.
- Oh, never?
- Never.
- This is the very first one...
- Oh, really?
- ...I've ever had, ever.
- [Marcus] Yeah.
- Yeah.
So, are you interested in, like,
any specific type of person or...
I thought I was interested in guys
at one point,
but then I tried watching
a little bit of, uh, gay porn, and...
- [laughs] Okay.
- It didn't...
- It didn't work out.
- No? Okay.
[both laugh]
And I did not like what I saw.
- [Chloe] Oh, okay.
- And I didn't feel anything.
So, you're sure
you're definitely straight?
- [Marcus] Yeah.
- Yeah.
How about you?
Um, well, I'm openly bi,
but I dated, uh, a few girls before,
a few guys, it's just,
you know, I'm just trying to find
the right person.
- [Marcus] True that.
- Yeah.
It's like, um... I like Asians.
- [laughing] Oh, Asians?
- [Marcus] Yeah.
Okay. [laughs]
- I'm a... I'm an Asian, and...
- Okay, yeah.
I'm not Asian. Okay.
I also like Mexicans.
- I like them, too.
- [Chloe] Okay.
Yeah, okay.
- Yeah.
- My, um...
- Oh.
- [waiter] Trout, guys?
Um, the steak and the... and the chips.
- Fish is right over here.
- Thank you.
[Marcus] Thank you.
- [waiter] No worries. Enjoy, guys.
- That's what I'm talking about.
[Chloe] Do you like Spider-Man?
- Yeah, I do.
- Who's your favorite Spider-Man?
Um...
- Tobey Maguire.
- [Chloe] Oh.
- That is my favorite.
- [Chloe] Oh, you see...
I quite like Andrew Garfield,
but I think Tom Holland, the current one,
he's all right, but...
Yeah, he's, um...
- No, he's an actual kid, so...
- [Marcus] He's okay.
- He didn't tickle my fancy.
- [Chloe] I guess...
- Hmm.
- [Marcus] Hm.
This has been a really nice date,
but I think it's getting a bit late.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
I had a nice time tonight. Thank you.
Thank you for the flowers, they're lovely.
- [Marcus] No problem.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
- Bye!
- [Chloe] Bye!
There wasn't really, like, a spark,
and it was a bit awkward for both of us.
It's kind of been, like,
a learning experience,
made me realize I like girls a bit more...
than men.
[man] Are you guys in love?
- What'd he say?
- Are we in love?
Um...
We're a bit more than in love.
Because we were a bit desperate,
- when we hit rough roads...
- [laughs]
...we just decide to cling on even more.
It's just nice and warm and comfortable
and stable now, I think.
- Steady.
- Yeah, yeah.
We're comfortable farting
in front of each other.
Yeah, that.
[both laugh]
[cat meows]
- [cat meows]
- [chuckles]
- Hello, Munchkin.
- [cats meowing]
[meows]
[Ruth] I've struggled my whole life
with friends,
and I've mostly really had friends
of the animal, imaginary kinds.
It would be nice to have
a real-life friend, I guess,
but I don't know if I will find one.
So, for the moment,
I've basically just latched onto Tom.
[laughs]
That... That one wasn't good enough.
We have to do it again.
- No, we don't!
- Yes, we do.
[chuckling] No, we certainly do not.
[jazz plays]
[engine turns over]
[Tom] I love my job.
It's really relaxing just driving around,
looking at the scenery.
Initially, as a railway enthusiast,
I was a bit, "Ew, buses, they're common."
Very, uh, snobbish of me.
But I then thought,
you know, while I couldn't find work,
maybe give them a try.
And here I am,
and I absolutely love it, uh...
Best job I've ever had.
Just around the corner is a house
Ruth and I are currently dreaming
about buying.
Really nicely located
next to the railway station.
It'd be nice to spend the afternoon
on the balcony,
just watching the buses and the trains
driving past.
I saw the bus come along,
and I just jumped on...
- [Tom chuckles]
- ...and then, for some reason,
Tom was in free dress...
- [Tom chuckles]
- ...and I had no idea why.
Aren't you supposed to be in uniform?
What? What?
What?!
- Serious?
- Yeah.
I told you I couldn't afford a ring.
I already bought it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Really?!
- Oh, for goodness' sake, just put it on!
[laughter]
[woman] And say yes.
[Ruth crying]
Come here.
[cheering and applause]
[Ruth laughs]
[woman laughs]
When it comes to physical beauty,
my idea is, a woman has to be beautiful,
but not to the point
where she looks like a model on a runway.
Definitely not. That's too beautiful.
Pretty much a fifty-fifty-looking girl.
That would be the best.
[narrator] Tonight, Michael is attending
a singles dinner in his local area.
It's the first of its kind to be run
by a local disability organization.
[people chattering]
- [Tamika] Hi, Michael.
- Hello, Tamika.
- How are you?
- [Michael] I'm good, yourself?
I'm great.
So, what are your hobbies?
Ten-pin bowling, pool,
um, watching television...
Nice. Now, that's nice.
- Yeah.
- And what are yours?
Mine is basketball, soccer,
football...
Ever since I was a little girl,
I always used to love sport.
Ah, so you're a bit of a tomboy type.
Correct, I am.
Ah.
- Who's got the Mediterranean pasta?
- [Michael] Here.
Thank you.
- That's me.
- [waitress] There you are.
Thank you.
Oh, have any of you seen
SpongeBob SquarePants?
Yes!
[imitates SpongeBob laughing]
[imitating Patrick Star] "Oh, SpongeBob.
If only you could see
how stupid you sound right now."
[imitates Mr. Krabs laughing]
"I love money!
Money, money, money, money, money."
[imitating Squidward] "Mistake? Ha!
The only mistake I ever made
was wasting my life at the Krusty Krab."
[imitating SpongeBob] "But a visit
to the Krusty Krab makes everyone happy!
And what could be better
than serving up smiles?"
[Tamika] Mm-hmm.
[Tamika] Are you a beer drinker, Michael?
- Nope.
- [Tamika] No?
I've always hated beer.
I don't even drink wine either.
I hate it.
Oh, wow.
[Michael] You see,
I'm a different kind of man.
I'm actually a teddy bear.
Aw, that's nice.
I like that.
[grunting]
- Hello.
Name's Michael.
Nice to meet you, Michael. I'm Carli.
Nice to meet you, Carli.
What do you do for work?
Um...
I... I run my own business.
Wow.
But sometimes
there have been complications.
Like, the financial side
on the business, it's...
become a bit, not blocked, but clogged up.
- You know what I mean?
- Yeah. [sighs]
But I've asked a friend of mine,
"Ah, can you fix that?"
"Yeah, I'll fix it, I know what it is."
Ah.
So, I can easily deal with that,
- 'cause see...
- Yeah.
For instance, I've gotta do it
tomorrow morning, because I've...
Probably tomorrow afternoon.
See if I can keep going on the...
on the business stuff.
But if it has to wait till the weekend,
and then she sees it and goes,
- "Oh, yeah, I gotta fix that again."
- Yes.
So, it's a bit frustrating.
- Hello.
- Hi.
My name's Michael.
Michael. My name's Amanda.
You have a very lovely bow.
Thank you.
And your hairstyle looks lovely as well.
And, so, tell me,
what are your hobbies and interests?
I like to collect toys
and dolls and things.
- Seriously?
- Yep.
That's what I like doing as well!
[Amanda] Really?
I've collected a lot
of Thomas the Tank Engine...
You like Thomas the Tank Engine?
- Yeah.
- I liked it when I was a kid.
- I still like it a bit now.
[Michael] Yeah.
Do you have a favorite Thomas character?
- No, there's too many of them.
- [Amanda] Yeah.
So, how old are you?
I'm 25.
I'm 21.
Have you had your birthday yet?
- Thank you.
- No, it's next week.
Oh, so you're 22?
Yeah, nearly.
So, you were born in 1997.
Same year Men In Black was released.
Is that a movie?
- [Michael] Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
You've heard of Asperger's?
Yes.
I actually have it.
So do I.
But mine's mild.
So is mine.
Wow. [chuckles]
I was 13 when I got a diagnosis,
so it was my first year of high school.
I never knew I had Asperger's
until my mother told me when I was 13.
That's not too bad.
Did she know
when you were younger, though?
I think so, but I don't know when.
- Yeah.
- When I was in primary school,
I often sat alone.
Yeah.
Do you mind if I ask you something?
- Yeah?
- [Michael] Um...
I actually enjoy... enjoy talking to you.
Me too.
I'd like to catch up with you
again sometime.
You never know...
What do you say?
Nice.
Hello.
[man] How's Cleo?
- What'd he say?
- How is Cleo?
She's all right.
She had a shed last night.
Do you want me to show you the s-skin?
[man] Yeah.
All right.
Got a surprise for her planned.
She doesn't know yet.
[Ruth] It's the skin.
- [man] Whoa.
- I'm very proud of my little girl.
[man] How do you feel
about four years together?
Yeah, it's cool. [exhales]
No need to sound so excited.
Sorry, I'm just... quietly elated.
- [Ruth chuckles]
- You're a goose.
It's like making out with Medusa.
[laughs] That's me.
[Tom laughs]
[purring]
- [driver] Hello, Thomas. Hello, Ruth.
- Hello.
Congratulations
on your fourth anniversary.
- What's going on?
- We're going on a date.
[Tom laughs]
Is that a Rolls-Royce with coach doors?
- This one's a vintage 1928 Chrysler.
- What did he say?
It's a Chrysler,
but we won't hold that against him.
No, we won't.
[horn honks]
[upbeat music plays]
[inaudible]
[Ruth grunts]
- Thanks very much.
- My pleasure.
- Do you have a business card?
- I do.
- [Ruth] Thanks. Can I have one?
- You sure can.
- There you go.
- Brilliant! Thank you so much.
- My pleasure. Enjoy your evening.
- Cheers!
What the...?
[Ruth] Oh.
[Tom chuckles]
[Ruth] Hmm.
Yeah.
Isn't this nice?
It's very à la The Bachelor.
- But it's still very cute.
- Well...
Well, very Bachelor,
because it's entirely scripted.
[laughs] Where's my script?
- Didn't you get it?
- No!
Who didn't email Ruth her script?
- [man] Sorry, I forgot.
- [laughs]
[slurping]
[exhales]
[smacking lips]
I wish I saw the warning signs
- when I met you.
- [laughing]
- [Ruth] I never professed to be a lady.
- Good.
[exhales]
[gulps]
Oh, that hurts.
Oh.
You're a cutie patootie.
And you have a cute patootie as well.
- Thanks.
- [Tom chuckles]
You're a really special girl, Ruth.
You're very different and very unique.
Well, you're a handsome boy.
- I am a handsome boy.
- You are.
[buzzing]
I'm a bit nervous,
but excited.
Hopefully it'll be love at first sight,
or whatever.
You know, like in the movies.
[narrator] After an unsuccessful
first date with Marcus,
Chloe is changing tack.
Chloe's date is with Lotus.
Lotus loves drag queens...
[cheering and applause]
...and the sound of parrots eating.
[crunching]
She hates people talking all at once...
[chattering]
...and loud machinery.
[drilling]
Hi, are you Chloe?
Oh, yeah, I'm Chloe. Are you Lotus?
- Yeah. Hi.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
Hi.
- Would you like to sit down?
- Yes, please.
[chuckles]
So, um, what kind of stuff are you into,
like, movies and stuff?
Um, I sort of...
- I like Sailor Moon, you know, the anime.
- Oh!
- I love Sailor Moon. [laughs]
- You're into anime?
- Yeah.
- Me too.
- [gasps] You do?
- I kind of stopped watching it for ages,
and then got back into it.
[Lotus] Oh, it's raining.
Okay, I'm gonna put my jacket on.
- I'm just getting cold.
- Yeah.
So are you, like, bi or lesbian?
- Yeah, I'm bisexual. I'm both.
- Okay. Yeah?
I thought I was, like, a lesbian
for the biggest time,
because I didn't feel
any attraction towards boys.
Yeah. I started to think, maybe it was
'cause the boys at my school were gross.
- [Chloe laughs]
- Um...
So, are you on the spectrum, too?
Yes. I didn't get diagnosed
until I was, like, 12.
'Cause, you know, sometimes with girls
on the spectrum...
- It's harder to...
- Yeah, you get diagnosed later.
Hello. We've got a mixed berry smoothie.
- That's me, thank you.
- And the iced...
And the iced choccy.
- Thank you.
- No worries.
[Lotus] Yeah, it was kind of weird.
When I was acting out, they didn't know
what was wrong with me.
They thought I was doing that
- because my parents got divorced.
- Oh.
They were always like,
"The kid's just going through a phase."
Like, I had sensory problems,
so I couldn't wear the socks,
and I couldn't wear the sweater,
and the school was like,
"Oh, she's just being annoying..."
- [Chloe] Oh, yeah.
- Yeah, and...
I was hated at my school,
absolutely hated,
because I would...
No one knew, really, what to do.
So, there's a sunflower farm,
um, down the road.
- Would you like to go and pick sunflowers?
- Oh, yeah, sure.
What's your favorite flower?
- Well, my name's Lotus, so...
- Oh, lotus.
- So probably a lotus.
- [laughing] Yeah. I get it.
- So, which way's the sunflower park?
- Oh, down there.
Alrighty.
- [Lotus] I wore the wrong shoes for this.
- Oh, so did I. Oh, God.
[Chloe chuckles]
[Lotus] Not to be lame,
but this reminds me of Minecraft.
Oh. [laughs]
Haha, yes,
the autistic girl likes Minecraft.
- This is cool. Like a little hidden spot.
- [Chloe] Yeah.
Feel that.
- Kinda hurts.
- [both laugh]
[Lotus] Uh...
I think it's going well.
You know, a lot better than I expected.
I really like her, you know.
We're, um, talking, getting along.
I was expecting, you know,
sort of awkwardness,
and that we wouldn't
have anything to talk about and...
Yeah, but we've just been
non-stop talking.
[Lotus grunting]
- [Lotus] Got it, thank you.
- [Chloe speaking indistinctly]
[Lotus] I think I got
a little bit nervous,
and I have trouble talking
when I'm nervous,
but I'm hoping that maybe she got that.
I just hope she knows that's the case,
and not that I was like,
- "I don't wanna be here."
- [man] Do you see Chloe as someone
- you could potentially date?
- Yes.
Yeah, um...
Yeah, it'd be cool
if she thought the same thing.
That looks like a little love heart.
- Oh, it does!
- Yeah.
- [Chloe] Quite cute.
- [Lotus laughs] Yeah.
[Chloe] Are you...
Are you all right?
Oh, yeah, I'm good, sorry.
I'm just spacing out. Um...
[Chloe chuckles]
- Alrighty, um...
- [laughing] Okay.
Uh...
Do you want this one?
- Oh, no, you can keep it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Okay, thank you.
- It's cute, I'll put it in my vase.
- [Chloe] Yeah.
Um, well, my mum's here
to pick me up. Uh...
- It was really nice to meet you.
- Very nice to meet you, too.
- It'd be cool to see you again.
- Oh, yeah. I would really like that.
- Oh, really? Okay, cool.
- Really, yeah.
I was really worried,
I didn't know if you liked me.
I was... I was worried too,
but that's really good. All right, um...
- Thank you. See ya!
- Bye!
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
[laughs]
[exhales]
- [man] Are you happy?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. [chuckles]
Oh, I can't stop smiling.
[laughs] Yeah.
[man] Can you describe for me
the perfect relationship?
Well, no relationship is perfect,
because perfection in a relationship
cannot exist in any way.
But you can make a relationship
a very healthy, stable,
loving relationship.
And whenever a person
is feeling bored or unhappy
in their relationship with someone,
all they need to do is stop
and do one thing that everyone should do:
smell the flowers.
They don't bloom every day.
[narrator] Michael is getting ready
for dinner with Amanda.
It will be his first ever date.
- [mother] Wow, how good do you look?
- [father] Million bucks.
- [Michael] That's what I wanna hear.
- Jeez, I love your shoes, mate.
Thanks, Dad.
- [mother] She'll be impressed.
- [Michael] Yep.
Speaking of which, this bit of paper
that Adam gave me,
I'll be keeping this on my person.
What is it?
Just dating points.
- Oh, okay.
- Dating advice.
"Be yourself, above all else.
Remain focused on your date.
Look for changes in the way she responds
to indicate if she's interested
in the conversation.
If she gives you short responses
with a flat tone,
take this as a sign to change the topic.
Keep your face relaxed
while maintaining eye contact."
[chuckles] Adam's a smart boy.
- [Michael] Indeed, he is.
- He gets it off me.
[mother] Yes.
Most guys wouldn't even think
about all that sort of stuff.
I wonder why.
Because that's the way
we've been created, I guess.
[laughs]
Yes, but I want to be different
from all men.
In what way?
An A-plus partner
looks like me.
[laughs]
- [laughs]
- [clears throat]
- I'm saying it because it's accurate, Mum.
- Yeah. [laughs]
Far-out, Mike.
- And...
- He's cute.
...when I do get married in the future,
not only will my wife be
my most crowning achievement, but also,
I've actually envisioned
a lot of family members in the future
saying this...
these words to my wife af...
after my passing.
- What the hell?
- After your passing?
[scoffs]
"Being your husband...
nothing made that man any happier."
- [laughs]
- [father] Mate...
- You're thinking too far ahead, mate.
- Dad, I always think ahead.
- [laughs]
- [mother] Yeah, but that's a bit too far.
Excuse me, everyone.
I need to do my final preparations
- for the date.
- [mother] Okay.
Thank you.
- So cute.
- [footsteps departing]
[Michael] Okay, which one?
[inhales]
Ah-ha!
[father] Don't wanna be late!
I know, I'm coming.
[mother] Don't forget the rose.
- I won't forget that either, Mum.
- [mother] Okay.
- No problem.
- [father] Don't forget your wallet.
- [father laughs]
- Nope. I never forget that, either.
- [mother laughs]
- My... My hair comb.
Um, just... Just bear with me
for a couple of minutes.
- We'll be there, we'll be there!
- [father laughs]
[mother] It's all right, Mike.
Ready.
- [mother] Okay.
- [father] Ready?
Yep, ready.
Good stuff.
All right, well, all the best, Michael.
- Good luck.
- Thanks, Dad.
Thank you.
Take care, Dad.
[father] Good. Now get outta here.
- Yep, see ya, Dad.
- [father] Nice flower, by the way, too.
- [Michael] See ya.
- [mother] Remember your brother's advice.
[Michael] Got it! Got it.
[birds squawking]
- Ah, thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
- Would you like some table water?
Uh, yes please, thank... thank...
Please and thank you.
[exhales]
[man] You all right?
Just can't believe that this is happening.
Little nervous.
Subtitles Diego Moraes(oakislandtk)
www.opensubtitles.org