[Michael] I've never actually dated anyone
in the past.
I've been dreaming about marriage
for years, ever since I left school.
I do feel like I'm ready.
[man] You all right?
Little nervous.
Just butterflies.
She won't see it there.
- Hey!
- Hello, Amanda.
- [Amanda] How are you?
- Oh, please, allow me.
- Thank you.
- I'm...
- [Michael] How have you been?
- I'm good. How are you?
I'm very good as well.
And, um...
this is for you.
Oh!
I love flowers.
- You do?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- It's my pleasure.
You know, I used to study flowers.
- I never knew that.
- Yeah. [laughs]
[Michael] Hmm.
So, um, what's been happening?
- Been working.
- Yeah.
Pretty sure. What have you been up to?
Not a lot, just work as well.
Yeah.
[Michael] Mmm.
Okay.
Mmm.
The last time we met,
you said that you love cats, right?
And you also said...
- Ah, thank you.
- [waitress] It's all right.
Thank you.
And, so what other hobbies do you have?
I've got birds I look after,
and I like to do a thing called cosplay
and go to conventions.
- Comic conventions?
- Yeah.
I do too!
- Really?
- Yep.
Yeah, have you been to one before?
Yes, the Oz Comic-Con.
I've been at that one.
Have you been to any others?
No, just that.
Yeah?
So, what else?
Hmm.
Might have to come back to that one...
[Michael] Uh...
I wanted to ask you,
when is your birthday again?
I had it on Wednesday.
- Oh, I missed it.
- Yeah.
When's yours?
Twentieth of March.
Same month as my cat's.
Yeah.
So, how many birds do you have?
About 12...
I think.
- I used to have more.
- [Michael] Oh.
So they flew away?
- Yep.
- Hmm.
That must have been saddening.
It's all right.
You just learn from it.
[inhales] I suppose.
[man] Would you like to take a break?
I'll be back, okay?
- Yeah, that's fine. That's fine.
- [Amanda] Oops.
Yeah.
[inaudible]
[man] Is there anything we can do,
Amanda, to help you feel better?
[Amanda] I think it's too formal.
I can't do this.
It's just bad anxiety.
Um, Cian?
- Cian?
- Hmm?
- Did I go too far?
- [Cian] Too far?
With... with the questions.
- [Cian] No, I don't think so. Not at all.
- Oh.
'Cause...
she seems a little bit quiet.
[Cian] Hmm.
- Um, here are your bag and your rose.
- Thank you.
[Michael] This doesn't have to be a date.
- Yeah.
- We can just, um...
have a friendly dinner as friends?
[Amanda] I think...
wait, and I'll do another time.
Yeah.
Shall I s...
see you to the... door?
If you want to.
[Michael] Okay.
Well, it was lovely seeing you again,
Amanda.
[Amanda] Mm-hmm.
[Michael] Sorry how things turned out.
It's okay.
[Michael] I do feel bad.
Don't feel bad.
[Michael] I just feel like I may have gone
too far with the questions.
[Michael sighs]
[Michael inhales deeply, then sighs]
Well, you take care of yourself, Amanda.
- You too.
- [Michael] And good luck.
Yeah.
[sighs]
Oh, well. [sighs]
That's... That's life, I guess.
Hi, I'm Maddi.
I'm single, and I'm on the spectrum.
I enjoy video games, books, and animals.
[Cian] How would you describe yourself,
Maddi?
I'm a very independent person.
Reasonably smart.
Uh, quirky.
[chuckles]
Always seem to, like, stand out
a little bit without even trying.
Or I'm funny without trying,
people tell me, so... [chuckles]
[Cian] What's something
you'd like people to know about you?
That just because I'm on the spectrum,
I'm not... I'm not...
I'm not dumb.
Some people can be
really condescending, like,
"How... are... you?" sort of thing.
I'm like, please, come on. [chuckles]
[Cian] How do you know
when you're in love?
Um, I can't really say for sure,
'cause I've never really been in love,
but I can only go by what...
like, what I've seen in movies and things,
so I'm not really...
Can't get into that too well, sorry.
[laughs]
[Cian] Can you describe
your ideal partner?
Tall, muscular...
rich. [chuckles]
[birds chirping]
So, what do you guys think
about me dating?
I think it's great if you wanna date.
Maybe you should date, get married,
and move out of home.
- Move out of home being the important one.
- Ah...
Well, how would you react
if I brought a boy home?
I think we'd cheer.
I'd have to vet him.
Make sure he was suitable for you.
Make him very uncomfortable.
Like we did with Montana,
- when she brought her boyfriend home.
- Right.
What do you think?
If I ever date, it'll be a couple of years
before he meets you guys, at least.
- Years?!
- [laughs] That's a bit rude.
Protect the poor guy for a little while,
for God's sake.
- Oh!
- Okay, well what about tonight?
- Let's talk about tonight.
- Who's going?
So, superheroes disco tonight,
down at Darling Harbour.
- And what are you going as tonight?
- Look for a Superman girl.
- [mother] Batgirl?
- Yes.
Maybe we look for a Batman tonight.
Okay, we're focusing a bit too much
on tonight.
Well, I think you gotta start somewhere,
and maybe we start with tonight.
What do you think are the qualities
of a man that you'd like to date?
Rich, muscular, tall.
- [scoffs]
- Eight-pack.
Like your mother landed.
[mother] Rich, muscular, tall. Mm-hmm.
You need to lower your standards.
[laughing] You're not gonna get tall,
muscular, eight-pack.
- You don't go to the gym.
- Where'd this eight-pack come from?
It looks good.
- You don't go to the gym!
- I don't want someone flabby.
Excuse you! You don't either.
- We were supposed to go to the gym today.
- I did go.
There's no shame in being picky
when it comes to love.
- [laughter]
- [Maddi] What?
- [Maddi] Have I got this on backwards?
- [mother] Yep.
These ones go down over your shoe.
- So, at the back, like...
- No, at the front, so turn it round.
[narrator] Maddi's mum Terri
is her greatest support.
There should be an elastic thing...
[narrator] She has taught Maddi
the communication skills
that have helped her step out
and socialize with her peers.
[Terri] Okay, pull it up.
Yep.
I would like to see her
have somebody in her life.
Clearly, I'm not gonna be here forever.
It would give me some comfort
to think that someone's there
to look after her
and she's there
to look after somebody else.
There we go. Wow, that looks cool.
Where's the mask?
Did you put it somewhere?
- No, I've got the mask here.
- Thank you.
[Cian] Do you ever worry
that she will end up alone?
Yeah, all the time.
Mmm. All the time.
[laughs]
That's good.
- [upbeat music plays]
- Hello there.
Ready to party.
[narrator] Dance For Abilities
is a social event run twice a year.
It's a rare opportunity
to bring people together
from the disability community.
You can't just dance with yourself,
find people to dance with.
Who do you know over here?
This man here,
you should be dancing with him.
And he's tall...
And a lot of money, he's Iron Man.
If he's ugly,
tell him to leave his helmet on.
All right, I get... I get the point.
I'll go talk to him.
All right, guys. Whoa, hello.
[Maddi] Would you like to dance?
[narrator] Maddi's dancing skills
have caught the eye of Sean,
who is also on the autism spectrum.
So, Sean, are you enjoying
yourself tonight?
Yes.
Okay.
How old are you, Sean?
Twenty-eight.
I'm 24.
I'm 28.
That's good. [chuckles]
Tell me about yourself.
What are some of your hobbies?
Um...
I'm trying to think.
Hmm.
Well, why... why don't I go first?
- My hobbies include video games...
- Yes.
- ...books, and animals.
What about for you?
What are some of your hobbies?
Um, I'm trying to think.
Do you like animals?
Yes.
Do you have any pets at home
that live with you?
- Yes.
- Cat or a dog?
I... I have a cat.
- Aww.
- I have a female cat named Marmalade.
- [Maddi] Is she a nice cat?
- Yes.
- [Maddi] Likes to play?
- [deep voice] Yes.
Um...
Should we head back inside, you think?
- Yes.
- Or would you like to stay out? Okay.
Conga line! Conga line!
Conga! Everybody in the conga line!
Whoo!
[Cian] So, Kelvin...
you just checking your hair?
- Looking good?
- Good. Good.
[Cian] Excellent.
So, you're ready to start?
I'm Kelvin. I'm 21.
I have autism,
a disability which helps me
concentrate on one thing,
rather than getting distracted by others.
[Cian] So, you think your autism
helps you to really focus on one thing.
How old were you when you were diagnosed
with autism, Kelvin?
Two years old.
[Cian] Wow, that's pretty young, hey.
Do you think you're different
to other people your age?
Yes.
[Cian] How are you different?
I have a different, uh, look in my face,
and different personality from others.
[Cian] How would you describe yourself?
I'm caring, smart,
gentle, considerate,
and professional.
[birds chirping]
[microwave chimes]
[narrator] Kelvin lives
with his single dad, David.
We'll share it, Dad.
Yeah, maybe we can share. Yeah.
This is so delicious.
Mmm-mmm.
[Cian] Would you like to see Kelvin
find a partner?
Yes, definitely, yes.
Being his father, yeah.
Yeah, I'd really like to see
if he can... [inhales]
uh, have... have a date,
and then girlfriend, have a partner,
and then, even better, to have a family.
That's nice, isn't it?
A bit hard, but, uh, hopefully, uh,
there will be a day
that, uh, this is possible.
[Cian] What's the hard part?
What do you think will be difficult?
I think it's the, like... [exhales]
uh, for him to communicate with somebody
which is at the same wavelength.
[Cian] How did you feel when you heard
- that he was on the spectrum?
- Uh, devastating,
but, uh, well, we have to come to terms,
and we have to try our best,
like, to help him.
Yeah, that's what we did,
like, all these years.
[Cian] Are you proud of him?
Oh, definitely.
I'm very proud of my son, yeah.
Hopefully, one day, he will...
He will find his partner.Yeah.
[Cian] Good to at least start
with maybe a bit of practice.
- Hmm, yeah.
- Practicing what?
- Dad?
- Hmm?
Practicing what?
Uh, go out dating
and seeing other, uh, people,
and seeing ladies...
Taking them out for dating, on dates?
Yep, have dinner, go to the movies, yeah.
Someone who is younger than you, Dad.
Yes, of course, yes.
For your dating, yes.
[Cian] What do you think love feels like?
Love feels like when a man
and woman get together,
they'll make a perfect bond.
[Cian] Do you think it's harder
for people with autism to find...
a relationship, to find a partner?
Some of them.
Some girls don't feel like dating
with someone in disa... with disabilities.
[birds chirping]
- [knocking]
- [Kelvin] What?
What is it, Dad?
[Cian] It's me, Cian.
Can we come in?
[Kelvin] Um, yes.
This is a cute R2-D2 toy.
Say hi, R2-D2.
Beep-boop, beep-boop, beep-boop.
And this is the poster
of my year 12 formal.
[Cian] Did you take a date to the formal?
I didn't.
I want to show you the drawings
that I made.
This is Chibi Tsuyu.
Eating frog cake.
This is Suzuha Amane.
She's strong-willed,
athletic,
like the one
that I'm looking forward to dating.
This is my original character,
Yuko Ezo.
She likes jellybeans, miso soup,
mackerel,
and carbonated drinks.
- [Cian] So you made up that character?
- Yes. It's for my story.
- [Cian] Where is your story?
- [Kelvin] It's...
[Cian] Wow, that is incredible.
You wrote all this?
[Kelvin] Yeah, I wrote it from my mind.
I'll still keep on writing
until I reach the end of this book.
- [Cian] I think that'll take you a while.
- [Kelvin] What...?
Oh.
T-That's enough. Excuse me.
- That's enough for now, okay?
- [Cian] Enough filming?
- Yes. Thank you.
- [Cian] We'll see you next time.
Bye!
[birds chirping]
[narrator] After Michael's date
didn't end well,
he wants to talk through the experience
with relationship specialist Jodi Rogers.
[incoming video call ringing]
- Hi, Michael!
- [Michael] Hello, Jodi.
How are things?
- Very well, how are things with you?
- Things have been pretty good.
Just work and that's about it.
[Jodi] Last time I was down there,
you were about to go out on a date
with somebody.
About the date, it ended too early.
Oh!
My date got overwhelmed by the atmosphere.
She had anxiety,
and I was starting to get a bad vibe
about things.
I just told her that if she had to go,
she was quite welcome to.
That's really supportive.
Till she had to leave,
did you feel like
you were getting to know her?
[Michael] Yeah, I was.
[Jodi] Yeah? What things
did you have in common?
We both love cats.
She loves comic conventions,
and I do as well.
Would you like to see her again?
I'm actually gonna be seeing her
on Sunday.
Well that's pretty good.
We'll be going
to a comic convention together.
[Jodi] Well that's excellent.
Do you think that the two of you
might find more things in common
with each other?
Who knows? We might.
It's very hard when the first time
you feel a little bit awkward
- and things don't go well.
- Yeah.
But this could be fantastic
on the weekend.
So, are you gonna wear a costume?
Yes, the Skipper off Gilligan's Island.
[laughs]
- That's a great costume!
- Because... Because Dawn Wells,
who played Mary Ann on the show,
will be there herself.
Oh, that's pretty exciting.
She's pretty much the total package.
- [laughs]
- She's not the hottest woman in the world,
she's beautiful,
but not extremely beautiful,
but she's definitely polite,
she's pure and very wholesome.
That kind of woman is very hard to find.
- Which is unfortunate.
- Okay.
[Jodi] So, if you had a girlfriend,
you'd want her to be more like Mary Ann.
Yes.
- I think that sounds like a good plan.
- Yeah.
[Jodi] All right, well, just have fun.
- Just have lots and lots of fun on Sunday.
- [Michael] Yep. Will do.
- [Jodi] It was lovely to speak to you.
- Likewise. Thank you for your time.
- See ya.
- All right, see ya. Take care of yourself.
[video call disconnects]
[Cian] Would you say that you're different
to other people?
Well, yeah, 'cause I've got a disability,
I'm on the spectrum,
people are always gonna look at me
as different from them,
and I know I'm different from them,
and that's fine, so...
If we're all the same,
the world would be pretty boring. [laughs]
[Cian] Would you like to go out with a guy
who is also on the spectrum?
Yes.
[exhales] Some people like to choose
partners who are the exact opposites
of them.
They've run out of things to talk about.
How is that so?
If you have lots in common,
you wouldn't run out,
it'd be endless conversations.
So, I think...
similar personality traits is quite good.
[birds chirping]
[narrator] It's Valentine's Day.
And Maddi is getting ready
for her very first date.
Wow, you look great!
Thank you, I know.
[Terri] You've got
your special necklace on.
[Maddi] Yes, it's a favorite.
Your watch is even color-coded
with your top, tonight.
It's called "successorizing."
Successoring?
Success with accessories.
- Oh, I see.
- Oh, wow.
Old people are so out of the loop, really.
[laughter]
Excuse me!
So, how are you feeling about tonight?
Nervous.
Your very first date.
[Maddi] Yes.
[Terri] On Valentine's Day.
I need a drink.
[laughing] You need a drink...
You don't even drink!
I don't care.
[Terri laughs]
- Can I take a photo?
- No. No.
- No!
Please, let me take a photo of you.
No, come on.
- I don't need to be fussed...
- I'm not gonna fuss. Just one quick photo.
- Please.
- Do not put it on Facebook.
[Terri] No, I won't put it on Facebook.
One... two...
- three.
- [camera clicks]
Okay.
First date photo.
Ooh! So excited!
- So excited!
- Please! Oh, God! No!
- God.
- [Terri] Have a good night.
- I'm nervous.
- This is why I don't want you there.
Okay. All right, all right.
- [Maddi] Leaving now.
- [Terri] Have fun!
That's important. Have fun.
- [father] Bye!
- [Terri] See ya.
[Terri inhales]
- Right, that's it, huh?
- She's off. She's launched.
Oh, my goodness.
- I wonder if all the coaching...
- I'm gonna be so nervous for her.
[narrator] Maddi is meeting Mark.
Mark likes
dinosaurs,
moonlit nights,
and the sizzle of Mongolian lamb.
[sizzling]
He doesn't like littering...
or rude words.
- [beep]
- [coins clink]
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Are you Maddi?
- Yes.
- I'm Mark. Nice to meet you.
- Mark, nice to meet you.
- Happy Valentine's Day.
- [Maddi] Thank you.
I got these for you.
Wow!
Thank you. Great. And this... [chuckles]
Thank you very much. They're lovely!
- Thank you very much.
- Right. Oh. It's nice to meet you.
[Maddi] Lovely.
Yeah. Okay.
[Mark] So, how's your day been so far?
[Maddi] Oh, yeah, pretty good.
Pretty good.
Much better now that there's sweets.
- Oh, yes.
- I love sweets.
[both chuckle]
[Maddi] Ah.
How are you feeling?
Uh...
Not too bad, actually.
Pretty... Pretty good.
Slightly nervous. But what about you,
how are you feeling?
I feel good.
- Really confident and excited.
- [Maddi] That's good.
Sorry to interrupt.
Would you like to order food?
For the main meal, I'll have the ravioli
with ricotta and spinach.
That would be nice.
[Maddi] And I will take...
the gnocchi, please.
The gnocchi?
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Thanks for that.
- Thank you.
- Enjoy your night.
- We will, thank you.
Okay.
What is your favorite thing in the world?
Dinosaurs.
- Oh, yeah?
- I'm into paleontology, stuff like that.
- Into what, sorry?
- Paleontology.
How do you pronounce that? Pal...
Paleontology.
Sorry, I haven't heard of that one.
- [laughing] That's okay.
- Paleontology.
- And that is?
- The study of prehistoric life.
Oh!
- Yes.
- Cool, that's pretty cool.
- But I'm...
- Palen... Sorry.
Palen... What is it?
- Pa-leon-to-lo-gy.
- Pa-leon...
- I'm sorry.
- No, it's all right, it's okay.
Paleontology, okay.
[Mark] Yeah.
[laughing]
How's yours?
It was nice, it was really nice.
- I love ravi... ravioli.
- [Maddi] Mmm.
You look beautiful.
Very, very beautiful.
Thank you, you look...
you look quite nice your... yourself.
Thank you.
And that's a really beautiful necklace.
You're very lucky to have that.
[Maddi chuckles]
It suits you well.
Thank you. Thank you.
I just wish this night didn't have to end.
[both laugh]
I can't remember
when I've had this much fun.
Yeah! It's been... certainly been...
certainly been
a very interesting evening, so...
[Mark laughs]
Well...
[Maddi] Thank you.
Thank you. Um...
[Mark mumbling]
Maybe we should dine and dash,
what do you reckon?
- [laughing] Oh, no!
- [Maddi laughs]
No? You don't... don't like that idea?
Subtotal...
We could grab our stuff
and run down the street.
What... What... What did you order?
The gnocchi.
Shall we pay for ours separately
or something?
Uh...
I've... I've got money, so, like...
Would you like to split?
How would you like it?
Actually, um, I'll pay on this.
[waitress] Yeah.
Rest on the card?
[Maddi] Yes. Okay.
Well, it's nice to meet you.
It was nice to meet you, Mark.
Thank you for...
I hope we meet each other again.
I had a great time,
and I hope we can do this again.
I had a good time too.
It would be good to hang out...
- Yes.
- ...again, like...
And I wish you all the best.
- Thank you.
- Thanks, once again.
Thank you.
- See you. Have a wonderful night.
- Bye, Mark. Thank you very much for...
You're welcome.
- ...the flowers.
- Thanks.
- You have a good night.
- You too.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
[Maddi] See ya.
[Cian] How did the date go, Mark?
Do you like Maddi?
Oh, she's really nice and very sweet,
and charming.
I feel like she's the type of person
that I'd love to spe...
have spend my life with.
- Hi, sweetheart.
- Hey, Mum.
How'd you go?
- Great.
- Did you have a lovely time?
Oh, loved it.
- Lovely meal, and enjoyed the company?
- Oh, yes.
- Oh, she was spectacular.
- Beautiful?
Oh, that's lovely, darling.
She was a lovely woman.
Yeah? That's awesome.
Never had that much fun in one night.
Can't remember the last time
I ever felt this good.
Oh, really? I'm so happy for you.
[Cian] So, how was tonight, Maddi?
Yeah, it was a good night.
I had fun. We had lots to talk about.
- He seems pretty smart, so, yeah.
- [Cian] Yeah?
Yeah, not many people interested in...
paleontology. I think I've got that right.
Hope that was right.
Add the eight-pack,
and that'll be perfection, so... [laughs]
[Cian] Do you think
you're a romantic person?
I will be.
[Cian] How would you ask a girl on a date?
If you liked someone,
how would you ask them?
Shall we go out for dinner together?
Or should we have some...
Shall we go out for a party...
and dance to the music together?
It'll be fun.
[birds chirping]
[narrator] As well as helping Michael,
relationship specialist Jodi Rodgers
has come to meet Kelvin
to work on his dating skills.
[knocking]
Often when I meet people
for the first time,
I'm really checking to see
what their ability is
with initiating conversation.
Sometimes I won't say hello to start with.
I'll wait and see whether they can
actually initiate verbally.
Because sometimes
people can't start a social interaction.
[speaking indistinctly in sing-song voice]
Cool, it's you. Jodi?
- Hello.
- Hey there.
- Welcome.
- [Jodi] Thank you.
Nice to meet you.
- My name's Kelvin.
- Nice to meet you, Kelvin.
It's called the autism spectrum,
because it's a spectrum.
Come on, follow me.
[Jodi] There is not two people
on the spectrum
where their autism presents
in the same way.
It is so diverse.
And that's its beauty.
It doesn't matter
whether you're on the spectrum or not,
everybody has a basic human right
and a basic human need
for connection and love.
So...
here's the girl.
Why do you want to have this girlfriend?
Because we... Because she's nice.
[Jodi] What will you and the girlfriend
do together?
Together... we should go out on... a date.
[Jodi] Yeah?
What else do girlfriends
and boyfriends do?
Hug and kisses?
[Kelvin] Hugs and... yeah.
Hugs and kisses.
So, would you like to do hugs and kisses?
Yes.
[Jodi] Yes.
When we go on our first date
with somebody,
what do we do on date number one?
We should introduce her by name...
first.
What if the girl
wants to sit down at the table?
What would you...
would be a good thing for you to do?
- Good thing...
- Like this, so you and I,
I'm... I'm... I'm gonna come...
Pretend Dad's not there,
'cause we don't want Dad
on the date, do we?
- What?
- [David laughs]
[Jodi] No way,
Dad's not coming on the date.
You show me what a gentleman
would do if... if...
Jodi's coming on... to meet you.
- Okay, you ready?
- Are you a gentleman?
[Kelvin] Hi.
Here you go. Here's your seat.
[chuckles] First of all,
you have to introduce...
Hi, my name's Kelvin Wong.
Nice to meet you.
My... My interests are manga and drawing
and computer.
Okay, first of all,
you want Jodi to sit down,
so we're on the same level.
- Don't we?
- [Kelvin] Yes.
Okay, so here's my chair here. Try again.
- [Kelvin] Okay.
- Okay, you ready?
Here I come...
- Hi, Jodi, my name is Kelvin Wong.
- [laughter]
Nice to meet you.
Hello, Kelvin. My name's Jodi.
- Then the chair. Let her sit down.
- Uh... Here's your chair.
No, go out and take the chair,
and then...
- Go out and take...
- No.
No, Kelvin. Stand up, get the chair out,
and let the lady sit down.
And then you say, here's your...
- Here's your chair, Jodi.
- Thank you very much.
- No, now you have to...
- [laughs]
That's a good...
When... When the girl...
She might already be sitting,
but remember,
before you move
onto talking about yourself,
we always do greetings first.
Greeting. Greeting.
Now, how... how are we going
to start talking with the girl about...
common interest?
Common...
Common inter...
If you just start talking about...
"Hi, I'm really into computers,
and I really like games and my iPad."
- No!
- Okay.
So the girls really like it...
if people, boys,
the first thing they do is ask them...
- [Kelvin] A question.
- Perfect.
Because then the girl thinks...
[gasps]
"Kelvin is really interested in me."
What would be a good first question
that you could ask her?
Ask her... What are your interests?
Oh, nice one.
- What are your interests...
- Perfect!
...by the way.
Perfect.
So what about if she comes back
and she says,
"I love animals
and everything about animals."
- [Kelvin] Ooh.
- [David laughs]
Cutie, indeed.
And they are so cute like toys.
They are like toys. What about...
And then the girl might ask you
a question...
Do you like animals?
I meant, I'm also interested in animals.
We should go to the koala park.
[laughs]
You're fine... Well, that was nice.
Why were you suggesting
that you go to the koala park?
It's because she likes animals.
I'm really proud. That is excellent.
If she likes something
that you don't like, is that okay?
So, say she says,
"Oh, my favorite anime is...
Sailor Moon."
[Kelvin] Yeah, uh, I used to...
What if she goes, "I like..."
[Kelvin] I used to watch it,
but not anymore.
Not anymore.
So is that okay that she likes
different anime and manga than you?
[Kelvin] Yes, like,
I get that Ouran High School
is bad taste, and I shouldn't watch it,
because of... 'cause it has mature themes.
Okay. So, we started talking about anime.
What did you do with your body?
Uh...
Looking away.
You're looking away.
- And that's a no.
- [Jodi and David laugh]
Exactly.
We've gotta keep the conversation being...
Fifty-fifty.
[Jodi] Fifty-fifty.
So, if you turn away and start talking
to yourself about your manga...
It's not a good thing.
It's not fifty-fifty, is it?
- I have to go to the bathroom.
- [Jodi and David laugh]
I'll be back.
It's good that you come in
and, like, show him all this.
Like, it's very, very useful for him.
Sometimes, like, man to man,
- it's difficult to get over to him.
- It's very hard.
Do you know, I think this is stuff that...
This is all the...
the really simple things...
- [David] Mmm.
- Um,
that we forget are so important
about social skills.
- Mmm-hmm, yes.
- But when you get to 21,
almost 22,
and he's desiring to have a relationship,
it's very hard for a dad to do that.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Isn't it?
- I find it really hard for me to...
- Yeah.
My job just is teaching people
- who are ready for...
- Um...
- ...dating and relationships.
- Yeah.
- And...
- Uh, for next one,
I'll ask her what movie we're watching.
Oh, have you been thinking about that?
Oh, I... I was thinking.
So, the most important thing
about the first date is...
Is the...
Is, um...
Greet her!
Greet her.
And what are you trying to find out?
You're trying to find out...
what you have in...
What?
- In common.
- Perfect.
You have to have some things
that are the same...
but you're allowed to have
some things that are...
- Different.
- Perfect.
I think your dating's gonna be good.
Just remember, we go up the steps...
slowly.
- Take it easy.
I think for Kelvin, the challenge
is just gonna be the beginning.
Challenges of social skills
with another person.
He's at the really beginning journey
of understanding what it is
to be with another person
and what that feels like,
and has to go through all the things
that we all go through.
The rejection,
finding out whether we've got
a good match with somebody...
At this stage in his learning,
it's... it's about practicing.
Just getting out there
and giving it a go,
and finding out
who's a good match for him.
Out you go, Jodi.
I'll see you anytime.
- Okay, see you, Kelvin!
- [Kelvin] See you!
[birds chirping]
- [Terri] Hey, bud.
- Hey.
How'd it go?! How'd it go?!
Tell me all about it!
Calm down. [chuckles]
How did it go?
Yeah, fine. He was a very nice guy.
Really? What did he look like?
- Oh, you've got a photo?
- Yes, I do.
Perfect!
Oh, he's very nice.
Yeah. Yeah...
Are they the flowers that he brought you?
[Maddi] Yeah.
- That was a nice touch, white roses.
- Yes, yes.
What did you do when you got the roses?
- I said thank you and hugged him.
- You hugged him?!
- Yeah, like...
- Show me. Show me what you did.
Just like that, sort of thing.
- Oh!
- I can do it properly standing up.
Oh, that's a good thing.
Don't make a fuss, honestly.
No, everything was okay?
All right, tell me all about him.
What do you mean?
Well, do you want to see him again?
- Yes.
- Perfect.
I think he looks
like he's good son-in-law material.
- Off you go, thanks. Off you go. Goodbye.
- [laughing]
[Terri] Okay, all right. [chuckles]
Parents, honestly... [sighs]
Jeez, Louise.
[Cian] Do you feel like you've got
a lot of love to give?
Yes.
All the people I know and care about,
they know me for my...
for my large heart,
which was once described as...
ten sizes too large.
[people chattering]
[camera shutter clicks]
Aha! There she is.
- Hello, Amanda.
- Hey!
Good to see you again.
Good to see you.
What are you dressed up as?
My character name's Riko.
From what?
An anime called Love Live!
- Ah.
- [Amanda] Yeah.
- Right.
- What's the book you've got?
Oh, that's a cookbook.
- Is that part of your character?
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
- Oh.
- Actually, um...
I wanted to see if I could get Dawn Wells
to, um, autograph this.
- Okay.
- [Michael clears throat]
Is there anywhere you wanna go?
Uh, yes. Um, you want to check out
a few places?
Okay.
Do you know much about Dawn Wells?
No...
- Barbara Eden?
- No.
- Barbara Feldon?
- [laughing] No.
Oh.
Then you probably haven't seen
Gilligan's Island.
- No.
- Or Get Smart.
- No...
- Or I Dream Of Jeannie?
- Mmm-mmm.
- Ah.
Oh, look, there's one
with a costume right now!
- [Amanda] The genie? Yeah!
- [Michael] Look! Look!
- [Amanda] I can see.
- That's her!
- Yep. [laughs]
- That's the costume.
If you ever wanted to have lunch
or dinner somewhere,
we don't have to...
have to go somewhere formal.
- Okay.
- We can go somewhere casual.
Yeah.
[Michael] Probably should've done that
the first time.
So, what do you wanna look at first?
There is something I want to get.
It's up this way.
[man speaking indistinctly]
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, no.
[Amanda] Everything okay?
- Don't you agree that that mask is creepy?
- Where?
Right there, the guy with the dark hair.
I refuse to watch those Halloween films.
- You don't like them?
- I hate 'em.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
- They're too scary.
[horror theme plays]
A little bird tells me
that you love plushes.
I do. I've got lots of them.
- Yeah?
- Yep.
I actually have a bit of an affinity
for them myself.
You like them too?
I keep it secret, though.
Oh. [laughs]
It's because they're...
They're not exactly something for men.
How are you feeling, by the way?
I'm okay.
- Are you sure?
- Yep.
Not feeling anxious in any way?
I want you to feel comfortable.
That's all I care about right now.
You recognize something?
Does look like you.
[laughs]
- [Michael] Should we buy this one?
- Yes.
Okay, then I'll get it for you.
- [Amanda] Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
I'll just grab that, thank you.
Thank you.
- There you are, Amanda.
- Thank you.
It's my pleasure.
It's a little gift from me to you.
Well, I...
I'll be heading off to, um, my...
that autograph and photograph thing.
- Yep.
- So, right now, um...
I have to say, it was really lovely
spending time with you again.
It was good to see you too.
Thanks.
Are you interested in, um, spending time
together again sometime soon?
I'll think about it.
Okay, you just have the time
to think it over.
- And, um, take care.
- See you later.
And good luck.
[Michael] She's still a great person
to spend time with.
We're... We're friends, probably.
Dating? Probably not.
[narrator] Michael's day
isn't over just yet.
He's about to meet his perfect woman.
There she is, right over there.
Right over there.
Oh, dear.
I can't believe this is happening!
- [Cian] You okay?
- Yep.
I can't remember the last time
I felt this excited.
Oh, dear.
It's finally happening!
[Dawn] There's the Skipper.
I've seen you all day.
[man] Hey, hello.
Dawn Wells!
- George Smith. What's your name?
- Michael Theo.
- Hello, Michael.
- It is... It is...
I can't tell you what an honor this is.
Since you were a little boy.
- Yep.
- Yeah.
- Yep. Since...
- Where'd you grow up?
- Wollongong.
- Where's that?
- That's on the south coast.
- Yes.
- Yep.
- You'd make a good Skipper!
- Thanks!
- Can I hug you?
- Yeah, sure, absolutely!
- Where's our camera? Right over here.
[gasps] Here's the Skipper!
- Have a good life, dear.
- You too, Dawn Wells.
- Thank you, dear.
- And also... God bless you.
God bless you too.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
[Michael] That's one of the most
cherished moments I've ever had in life.
It was quite a privilege.
Really loved it.
[Cian] Do you have anything else
you want to say?
Oh, yes.
One thing that I'd like to...
One message that I'd like to send
to all women in the world.
I would be the kind of partner
that is able to provide
five things that every woman needs.
Love, respect, happiness, support,
and security.
[cell phone ringing]
- [Terri] Oops.
- [father] Uh-oh. Here's trouble.
- Oh, my goodness, who's that?
- Who's that?
Hello?
[Mark] Hello, it's... This is Mark.
- Hi, Mark, how are you? It's Maddi.
- [Mark] I'm...
How... I'm good. How are you, Maddi?
Yeah, I'm doing pretty good.
- [whispering]
- [Mark] Oh, that's.. that's great.
- We've...
- [Mark] That's wonderful to hear.
I've recently adopted a new puppy.
- [Mark] Awesome! That's great.
- [Maddi] Yeah.
- He's a...
- [Mark] What kind...
He's a miniature schnauzer
and his name is Arnold.
- [Mark] Arnold.
- Yeah.
Oh, lovely, lovely.
[Mark chuckles]
- That's wonderful to hear.
- Ask him what he's been doing.
[Mark] Great, you've got a companion.
Yes, a new best friend.
- Ask him...
- [Mark] Yeah.
Also, I've been ringing you up because
I was just thinking, would you like to go
on a second date to Sydney next Friday?
- [whispers] Next Friday.
- Yes, that would be...
Yes, I would like... I would like to do
another catch-up. That'd be interesting.
[Mark] Yes.
- [whispers] Where?
- [Mark] And I was thinking maybe I could
take you to the Australian Museum, and...
we can go for a walk through Hyde Park.
Yeah, that sounds like...
That sounds like it'll be good.
[Mark] Yeah, or whatever, you know.
- Yeah.
- You need to...
[Mark] Because I had such a great time
the last time.
It was really wonderful,
and I would love to do something
like that again.
Yeah, it was... it was nice, wasn't it?
It was pleasant.
Will he remember? Ask him.
Oh, well, you'll...
You'll probably remember what I look like
after one date, I think?
[Mark] Of course I will.
Great.
[Mark] Yes, I mean...
I can never forget a beautiful face.
Thank you, that's very kind to say.
- [father] Nice work.
- [Mark] It's okay. It's...
- It's a pleasure.
- [chuckles]
That's okay.
[Mark laughs]
Anyway, thanks for your time, Maddi.
And I look forward to seeing you again.
No problem, I'll... I'll see you later.
- [Mark] Have a wonderful week.
- You too.
[Mark] I'll see you next Friday.
See you then.
- [Mark] Okay, goodbye.
- Bye!
Wow!
Okay.
Such a pretty face.
- So, can't forget a pretty face! Whoo-hoo!
- [father] Mmm!
This is exactly why you guys
are not coming.
Maybe we should go and meet his parents.
No!
Make sure he comes
from the right background.
Right background. Sounds like it is.
[Maddi laughs]
[Terri] What?
No. You're rushing things. No.
Oh. Okay.
[Cian] How would you feel about having
a partner and having love in your life?
It would make me feel confident.
I got pictures of girls in my brain,
right now.
They look cute.
And they make me feel like
I'm gonna love them.
[narrator] It's Friday...
[humming]
and Kelvin is getting ready
for a special night.
His first ever date.
Okay, you're all ready to go.
- Okay.
- Thanks, Dad.
Just enjoy yourself tonight, huh?
Just remember what Jodi said
in the morning.
- Do a greeting with her.
- Yeah.
- And then introduce each other.
And then talk to each other
about interests.
- That's right.
- Fifty-fifty.
That's right. [chuckles]
You don't need to say it.
Just in your mind. Just remember it, yeah?
- [Kelvin] Okay.
- Okay.
Yeah.
[Kelvin] Looks like
I'll be having fun tonight.
Subtitles Diego Moraes(oakislandtk)
www.opensubtitles.org